<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:56:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Dark Nexus Between Harm Groups and &#8216;The Com&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 12:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2992]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[303]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[404]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[545]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[555]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6996]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[7997]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[8884]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advance Auto Parts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ali Winston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALPHV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aspertaine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beige Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Cat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BreachForums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChumLul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrowdStrike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVLT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Der Spiegel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doxbin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EA Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H3ll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harm Nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Thomas Andrew McCarty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judische]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalana Limkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaskar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kayte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kingbob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kya Christian Nelson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leak Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending Tree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mandiant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark rasch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MGM Resorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neiman Marcus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicholas "Convict" Ceraolo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NMK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Michael Urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pompompurin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCMP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal Canadian Mounted Police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sagar "Weep" Singh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santander Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scattered Spider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slit Town]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sosa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SWATting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ticketmaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNC5537]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ViLE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vSphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A cyberattack that shut down some of the top casinos in Las Vegas last year quickly became one of the most riveting security stories of 2023: It was the first known case of native English-speaking hackers in the United States and Britain teaming up with ransomware gangs based in Russia. But that made-for-Hollywood narrative has eclipsed a far more hideous trend: Many of these young, Western cybercriminals are also members of fast-growing online groups that exist solely to bully, stalk, harass and extort vulnerable teens into physically harming themselves and others.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cyberattack that shut down two of the top casinos in Las Vegas last year quickly became one of the most riveting security stories of 2023. It was the first known case of native English-speaking hackers in the United States and Britain teaming up with ransomware gangs based in Russia. But that made-for-Hollywood narrative has eclipsed a far more hideous trend: Many of these young, Western cybercriminals are also members of fast-growing online groups that exist solely to bully, stalk, harass and extort vulnerable teens into physically harming themselves and others.</p>
<div id="attachment_68692" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68692" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-68692" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vegasnight-ss.png" alt="" width="748" height="498" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vegasnight-ss.png 885w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vegasnight-ss-768x511.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vegasnight-ss-782x520.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68692" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock.</p></div>
<p>In September 2023, a Russian ransomware group known as <strong>ALPHV/Black Cat</strong> claimed credit for an intrusion at the <strong>MGM Resorts</strong> hotel chain that quickly brought MGM&#8217;s casinos in Las Vegas to a standstill. While MGM was still trying to evict the intruders from its systems, an individual who claimed to have firsthand knowledge of the hack contacted multiple media outlets to offer interviews about how it all went down.</p>
<p>One <a href="https://archive.ph/MuU4s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">account of the hack</a> came from a 17-year-old in the United Kingdom, who told reporters the intrusion began when one of the English-speaking hackers phoned a tech support person at MGM and tricked them into resetting the password for an employee account.</p>
<p>The security firm <strong>CrowdStrike</strong> dubbed the group &#8220;<strong>Scattered Spider</strong>,&#8221; a recognition that the MGM hackers came from different cliques scattered across an ocean of Telegram and Discord servers dedicated to financially-oriented cybercrime.</p>
<p>Collectively, this archipelago of crime-focused chat communities is known as &#8220;<strong>The Com</strong>,&#8221; and it functions as a kind of distributed cybercriminal social network that facilitates instant collaboration.</p>
<p>But mostly, The Com is a place where cybercriminals go to boast about their exploits and standing within the community, or to knock others down a peg or two. Top Com members are constantly sniping over who pulled off the most impressive heists, or who has accumulated the biggest pile of stolen virtual currencies.</p>
<p>And as often as they extort victim companies for financial gain, members of The Com are trying to wrest stolen money from their cybercriminal rivals &#8212; often in ways that spill over into <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/09/sim-swapper-abducted-beaten-held-for-200k-ransom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">physical violence in the real world</a>.</p>
<p>CrowdStrike would go on to produce and <a href="https://www.crowdstrikeswag.com/Scattered-Spider-Figurine-P723.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sell Scattered Spider action figures</a>, and it featured <a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1787661809547088194" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a life-sized Scattered Spider sculpture</a> at this year&#8217;s RSA Security Conference in San Francisco.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-68665" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/scatteredspider-figure.png" alt="" width="750" height="536" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/scatteredspider-figure.png 945w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/scatteredspider-figure-768x549.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/scatteredspider-figure-782x559.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/scatteredspider-figure-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>But marketing security products and services based on specific cybercriminal groups can be tricky, particularly if it turns out that robbing and extorting victims is by no means the most abhorrent activity those groups engage in on a daily basis.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity examined the Telegram user ID number of the account that offered media interviews about the MGM hack &#8212; which corresponds to the screen name &#8220;<strong>@Holy&#8221;</strong> &#8212; and found the same account was used across a number of cybercrime channels that are entirely focused on extorting young people into harming themselves or others, and recording the harm on video.</p>
<h2>HOLY NAZI</h2>
<p>Holy was known to possess multiple prized Telegram usernames, including @bomb, @halo, and @cute, as well as one of the highest-priced Telegram usernames ever put up for sale: <strong>@nazi</strong>.</p>
<p>In one post on a Telegram channel dedicated to youth extortion, this same user can be seen asking if anyone knows the current Telegram handles for several core members of 764, an extremist group known for victimizing children through coordinated online campaigns of extortion, doxing, swatting and harassment.</p>
<p>People affiliated with harm groups like 764 will often recruit new members by lurking on gaming platforms, social media sites and mobile applications that are popular with young people, including <strong>Discord</strong>, <strong>Minecraft</strong>, <strong>Roblox</strong>, <strong>Steam</strong>, <strong>Telegram</strong>, and <strong>Twitch</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;This type of offence usually starts with a direct message through gaming platforms and can move to more private chatrooms on other virtual platforms, typically one with video enabled features, where the conversation quickly becomes sexualized or violent,&#8221; warns a <a href="https://www.rcmp-grc.gc.ca/en/news/2024/rcmp-reminds-canadians-violent-online-groups-targeting-youth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent alert</a> from the <strong>Royal Canadian Mounted Police</strong> (RCMP) about the rise of sextortion groups on social media channels.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the tactics being used by these actors is sextortion, however, they are not using it to extract money or for sexual gratification,&#8221; the RCMP continued. &#8220;Instead they use it to further manipulate and control victims to produce more harmful and violent content as part of their ideological objectives and radicalization pathway.&#8221;</p>
<p>The 764 network is among the most populated harm communities, but there are plenty more. Some of the largest such known groups include <strong>CVLT</strong>, <strong>Court</strong>, <strong>Kaskar</strong>, <strong>Leak Society</strong>, <strong>7997</strong>, <strong>8884</strong>, <strong>2992</strong>, <strong>6996</strong>, <strong>555</strong>, <strong>Slit Town</strong>, <strong>545</strong>, <strong>404</strong>, <strong>NMK</strong>, <strong>303</strong>, and <strong>H3ll</strong>.</p>
<p>In March, a consortium of reporters from <em>Wired,</em> <em>Der Spiegel</em>, <em>Recorder</em> and <em>The Washington Post</em> examined millions of messages across more than 50 Discord and Telegram chat groups.</p>
<p>&#8220;The abuse perpetrated by members of com groups is extreme,&#8221; Wired&#8217;s <strong>Ali Winston</strong> <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/764-com-child-predator-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;They have coerced children into sexual abuse or self-harm, causing them to deeply lacerate their bodies to carve &#8216;cutsigns&#8217; of an abuser’s online alias into their skin.&#8221; The story continues:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Victims have flushed their heads in toilets, attacked their siblings, killed their pets, and in some extreme instances, attempted or died by suicide. Court records from the United States and European nations reveal participants in this network have also been accused of robberies, in-person sexual abuse of minors, kidnapping, weapons violations, swatting, and murder.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Some members of the network extort children for sexual pleasure, some for power and control. Some do it merely for the kick that comes from manipulation. Others sell the explicit CSAM content produced by extortion on the dark web.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity has learned Holy is the 17-year-old who was <a href="https://www.westmidlands.police.uk/news/west-midlands/news/news/2024/july/walsall-teenager-arrested-in-joint-west-midlands-police-and-fbi-operation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested in July 2024</a> by the U.K.&#8217;s West Midlands Police as part of a joint investigation with the FBI into the MGM hack.</p>
<p>Early in their cybercriminal career (as a 15-year-old), @Holy went by the handle &#8220;<strong>Vsphere</strong>,&#8221; and was a proud member of the <strong>LAPSUS$</strong> cybercrime group. Throughout 2022, LAPSUS$ <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/leaked-chats-show-lapsus-stole-t-mobile-source-code/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">would hack and social engineer their way into some of the world&#8217;s biggest technology companies</a>, including <strong>EA Games,</strong> <strong>Microsoft</strong>, <strong>NVIDIA</strong>, <strong>Okta</strong>, <strong>Samsung</strong>, and <strong>T-Mobile</strong>.</p>
<h2>JUDISCHE/WAIFU</h2>
<p>Another timely example of the overlap between harm communities and top members of The Com can be found in a group of criminals who recently stole obscene amounts of customer records from users of the cloud data provider <strong>Snowflake</strong>.</p>
<p>At the end of 2023, malicious hackers figured out that many major companies have uploaded massive amounts of valuable and sensitive customer data to Snowflake servers, all the while protecting those Snowflake accounts with little more than a username and password (no multi-factor authentication required). The group then searched darknet markets for stolen Snowflake account credentials, and began raiding the data storage repositories used by some of the world&#8217;s largest corporations.</p>
<p>Among those that had data exposed in Snowflake was <strong>AT&amp;T</strong>, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/07/hackers-steal-phone-sms-records-for-nearly-all-att-customers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disclosed in July</a> that cybercriminals had stolen personal information and phone and text message records for roughly 110 million people &#8212; nearly all its customers.</p>
<p>A report on the extortion group from the incident response firm <strong>Mandiant</strong> notes that Snowflake victim companies were privately approached by the hackers, who demanded a ransom in exchange for a promise not to sell or leak the stolen data. All told, more than 160 organizations were extorted, including <strong>TicketMaster</strong>, <strong>Lending Tree</strong>, <strong>Advance Auto Parts</strong> and <strong>Neiman Marcus</strong>.</p>
<p>On May 2, 2024, a user by the name &#8220;<strong>Judische</strong>&#8221; claimed on the fraud-focused Telegram channel <strong>Star Chat</strong> that they had hacked <strong>Santander Bank</strong>, one of the first known Snowflake victims. Judische would repeat that claim in Star Chat on May 13 &#8212; the day before Santander publicly disclosed a data breach &#8212; and would periodically blurt out the names of other Snowflake victims before their data even went up for sale on the cybercrime forums.</p>
<p>A careful review of Judische&#8217;s account history and postings on Telegram shows this user is more widely known under the nickname &#8220;<strong>Waifu</strong>,&#8221; an early moniker that corresponds to one of the more accomplished SIM-swappers in The Com over the years.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sim-swapping/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a SIM-swapping attack</a>, the fraudsters will phish or purchase credentials for mobile phone company employees, and use those credentials to redirect a target&#8217;s mobile calls and text messages to a device the attackers control.</p>
<p>Several channels on Telegram maintain a frequently updated leaderboard of the 100 richest SIM-swappers, as well as the hacker handles associated with specific cybercrime groups (Waifu is ranked #24). That leaderboard has long included Waifu on a roster of hackers for a group that called itself &#8220;<strong>Beige</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Beige members were implicated in two stories published here in 2020. The first was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/08/voice-phishers-targeting-corporate-vpns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an August 2020 piece called Voice Phishers Targeting Corporate VPNs</a>, which warned that the COVID-19 epidemic had brought a wave of voice phishing or &#8220;vishing&#8221; attacks that targeted work-from-home employees via their mobile devices, and tricked many of those people into giving up credentials needed to access their employer&#8217;s network remotely.</p>
<p>Beige group members also have claimed credit for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/11/godaddy-employees-used-in-attacks-on-multiple-cryptocurrency-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a breach at the domain registrar GoDaddy</a>. In November 2020, intruders thought to be associated with the Beige Group tricked a GoDaddy employee into installing malicious software, and with that access they were able to redirect the web and email traffic for multiple cryptocurrency trading platforms.</p>
<p>The Telegram channels that Judische and his related accounts frequented over the years show this user divides their time between posting in SIM-swapping and cybercrime cashout channels, and harassing and stalking others in harm communities like Leak Society and Court.</p>
<p>Mandiant has attributed the Snowflake compromises to a group it calls “<strong>UNC5537</strong>,” with members based in North America and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Turkey</a>. KrebsOnSecurity has learned Judische is a 26-year-old software engineer in Ontario, Canada.</p>
<p>Sources close to the investigation into the Snowflake incident tell KrebsOnSecurity the UNC5537 member in Turkey is <strong>John Erin Binns</strong>, an elusive American man indicted by the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> (DOJ) for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2021 breach at T-Mobile</a> that exposed the personal information of at least 76.6 million customers.</p>
<p>Binns is currently in custody in a Turkish prison and fighting his extradition. Meanwhile, he has been suing almost every federal agency and agent that contributed investigative resources to his case.</p>
<p>In June 2024, a Mandiant employee <a href="https://archive.ph/dI52m#selection-1721.0-1721.339" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told Bloomberg</a> that UNC5537 members have made death threats against cybersecurity experts investigating the hackers, and that in one case the group used artificial intelligence to create fake nude photos of a researcher to harass them.<span id="more-68600"></span></p>
<h2>ViLE</h2>
<p>In June 2024, two American men <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/two-men-plead-guilty-computer-intrusion-and-aggravated-identity-theft-hacking-federal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty</a> to hacking into a <strong>U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency</strong> (DEA) online portal that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/05/dea-investigating-breach-of-law-enforcement-data-portal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tapped into 16 different federal law enforcement databases</a>.  <strong>Sagar &#8220;Weep&#8221; Singh</strong>, a 20-year-old from Rhode Island, and <strong>Nicholas &#8220;Convict&#8221; Ceraolo</strong>, 25, of Queens, NY, were both active in SIM-swapping communities.</p>
<p>Singh and Ceraolo hacked into a number of foreign police department email accounts, and used them to make phony &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/hackers-gaining-power-of-subpoena-via-fake-emergency-data-requests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">emergency data requests</a>&#8221; to social media platforms seeking account information about specific users they were stalking. According to the government, in each case the men impersonating the foreign police departments told those platforms the request was urgent because the account holders had been trading in child pornography or engaging in child extortion.</p>
<p>Eventually, the two men formed part of a group of cybercriminals known to its members as “<strong>ViLE</strong>,” who specialize in obtaining personal information about third-party victims, which they then used to harass, threaten or extort the victims, a practice known as “doxing.”</p>
<p>The U.S. government says Singh and Ceraolo worked closely with a third man &#8212; referenced in the indictment as co-conspirator #1 or &#8220;CC-1&#8221; &#8212; to administer a doxing forum where victims could pay to have their personal information removed.</p>
<p>The government doesn&#8217;t name CC-1 or the doxing forum, but CC-1&#8217;s hacker handle is &#8220;<strong>Kayte</strong>&#8221; (a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>KT</strong>&#8220;) which corresponds to the nickname of a 23-year-old man who lives with his parents in Coffs Harbor, Australia. For several years (with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/a-closer-look-at-the-lapsus-data-extortion-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a brief interruption</a>), KT has been the administrator of a truly vile doxing community known as the <strong>Doxbin</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_63060" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-63060" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-63060" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/ViLE.png" alt="" width="748" height="494" /><p id="caption-attachment-63060" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of the website for the cybercriminal group &#8220;ViLE.&#8221; Image: USDOJ.</p></div>
<p>People whose names and personal information appear on the Doxbin can quickly find themselves the target of extended harassment campaigns, account hacking, SIM-swapping and even <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=swatting" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>swatting</strong></a> &#8212; which involves falsely reporting a violent incident at a target&#8217;s address to trick local police into responding with potentially deadly force.</p>
<p>A handful of Com members targeted by federal authorities have gone so far as to perpetrate swatting, doxing, and other harassment against the same federal agents who are trying to unravel their alleged crimes. This has led some investigators working cases involving the Com to begin redacting their names from affidavits and indictments filed in federal court.</p>
<p>In January 2024, KrebsOnSecurity broke the news that prosecutors in Florida had <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/fla-man-charged-in-sim-swapping-spree-is-key-suspect-in-hacker-groups-oktapus-scattered-spider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">charged a 19-year-old alleged Scattered Spider member</a> named <strong>Noah Michael Urban</strong> with wire fraud and identity theft. That story recounted how Urban&#8217;s alleged hacker identities &#8220;<strong>King Bob</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Sosa</strong>&#8221; inhabited a world in which rival cryptocurrency theft rings frequently settled disputes through so-called <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/09/violence-as-a-service-brickings-firebombings-shootings-for-hire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;violence-as-a-service&#8221; offerings</a> &#8212; hiring strangers online to perpetrate firebombings, beatings and kidnappings against their rivals.</p>
<p>Urban&#8217;s indictment shows the name of the federal agent who testified to it has been blacked out:</p>
<div id="attachment_68663" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68663" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68663" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sosa-redact.png" alt="" width="750" height="480" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sosa-redact.png 899w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sosa-redact-768x491.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sosa-redact-782x500.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68663" class="wp-caption-text">The final page of Noah Michael Urban&#8217;s indictment shows the investigating agent redacted their name from charging documents.</p></div>
<h2>HACKING RINGS, STALKING VICTIMS</h2>
<p>In June 2022, this blog told the story of two men charged with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/12/hacked-ring-cams-used-to-record-swatting-victims/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hacking into the Ring home security cameras</a> of a dozen random people and then methodically swatting each of them. Adding insult to injury, the men used the compromised security cameras to record live footage of local police swarming those homes.</p>
<div id="attachment_62212" style="width: 260px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-62212" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-62212" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/JTAMcCarty-Mugshot.png" alt="" width="250" height="307" /><p id="caption-attachment-62212" class="wp-caption-text">McCarty, in a mugshot.</p></div>
<p><strong>James Thomas Andrew McCarty</strong>, Charlotte, N.C., and <strong>Kya &#8220;Chumlul&#8221; Nelson</strong>, of Racine, Wisc., conspired to hack into <strong>Yahoo</strong> email accounts belonging to victims in the United States. The two would check how many of those Yahoo accounts were associated with Ring accounts, and then target people who used the same password for both accounts.</p>
<p>The <strong>Telegram</strong> and <strong>Discord</strong> aliases allegedly used by McCarty — “<strong>Aspertaine</strong>” and “<strong>Couch</strong>,” among others — correspond to an identity that was active in certain channels dedicated to SIM-swapping.</p>
<p>What KrebsOnSecurity didn&#8217;t report at the time is that both ChumLul and Aspertaine were active members of CVLT, wherein those identities clearly participated in harassing and exploiting young teens online.</p>
<p>In June 2024, McCarty was sentenced to seven years in prison after pleading guilty to making hoax calls that elicited police SWAT responses. Nelson also pleaded guilty and received a seven-year prison sentence.</p>
<h2>POMPOMPURIN</h2>
<p>In March 2023, U.S. federal agents in New York announced they&#8217;d arrested &#8220;<strong>Pompompurin</strong>,&#8221; <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/03/feds-charge-ny-man-as-breachforums-boss-pompompurin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the alleged administrator of Breachforums</a>, an English-language cybercrime forum where hacked corporate databases frequently appear for sale. In cases where the victim organization isn&#8217;t extorted in advance by hackers, being listed on Breachforums has often been the way many victims first learned of an intrusion.</p>
<p>Pompompurin had been a nemesis to the FBI for several years. In November 2021, KrebsOnSecurity broke the news that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/11/hoax-email-blast-abused-poor-coding-in-fbi-website/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thousands of fake emails about a cybercrime investigation were blasted out from the FBI’s email systems and Internet addresses</a>.</p>
<p>Pompompurin took credit for that stunt, and said he was able to send the FBI email blast by exploiting a flaw in an FBI portal designed to share information with state and local law enforcement authorities. The FBI later acknowledged that a software misconfiguration allowed someone to send the fake emails.</p>
<p>In December, 2022, KrebsOnSecurity detailed how <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/12/fbis-vetted-info-sharing-network-infragard-hacked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hackers active on BreachForums had infiltrated the FBI’s InfraGard program</a>, a vetted network designed to build cyber and physical threat information sharing partnerships with experts in the private sector. The hackers impersonated the CEO of a major financial company, applied for InfraGard membership in the CEO’s name, and were granted admission to the community.</p>
<p>The feds named Pompompurin as 21-year-old Peekskill resident <strong>Conor Brian Fitzpatrick</strong>, who was originally charged with one count of conspiracy to solicit individuals to sell unauthorized access devices (stolen usernames and passwords). But after FBI agents raided and searched the home where Fitzpatrick lived with his parents, prosecutors tacked on charges for possession of child pornography.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-68703" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/pompom.png" alt="" width="756" height="568" /></p>
<h2>DOMESTIC TERRORISM?</h2>
<p>Recent actions by the DOJ indicate the government is well aware of the significant overlap between leading members of The Com and harm communities. But the government also is growing more sensitive to the criticism that it can often take months or years to gather enough evidence to criminally charge some of these suspects, during which time the perpetrators can abuse and recruit countless new victims.</p>
<p>Late last year, however, the DOJ signaled a new tactic in pursuing leaders of harm communities like 764: Charging them with domestic terrorism.</p>
<p>In December 2023, the government <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.hid.167961/gov.uscourts.hid.167961.1.0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">charged</a> (PDF) a Hawaiian man with possessing and sharing sexually explicit videos and images of prepubescent children being abused. Prosecutors <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-hi/pr/hilo-man-arrested-child-pornography-violation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">allege</a> <strong>Kalana Limkin</strong>, 18, of Hilo, Hawaii, admitted he was an associate of CVLT and 764, and that he was the founder of a splinter harm group called <strong>Cultist</strong>. Limkin&#8217;s Telegram profile shows he also was active on the harm community Slit Town.</p>
<p>The relevant citation from Limkin&#8217;s complaint reads:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Members of the group &#8216;764&#8217; have conspired and continue to conspire in both online and in-person venues to engage in violent actions in furtherance of a Racially Motivated Violent Extremist ideology, wholly or in part through activities that violate federal criminal law meeting the statutory definition of Domestic Terrorism, defined in Title 18, United States Code, § 2331.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Experts say charging harm groups under <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/2331" target="_blank" rel="noopener">anti-terrorism statutes</a> potentially gives the government access to more expedient investigative powers than it would normally have in a run-of-the-mill criminal hacking case.</p>
<p>&#8220;What it ultimately gets you is additional tools you can use in the investigation, possibly warrants and things like that,&#8221; said <strong>Mark Rasch</strong>, a former U.S. federal cybercrime prosecutor and now general counsel for the New York-based cybersecurity firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>. &#8220;It can also get you additional remedies at the end of the case, like greater sanctions, more jail time, fines and forfeiture.&#8221;</p>
<p>But Rasch said this tactic can backfire on prosecutors who overplay their hand and go after someone who ends up challenging the charges in court.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you&#8217;re going to charge a hacker or pedophile with a crime like terrorism, that&#8217;s going to make it harder to get a conviction,&#8221; Rasch said. &#8220;It adds to the prosecutorial burden and increases the likelihood of getting an acquittal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rasch said it&#8217;s unclear where it is appropriate to draw the line in the use of terrorism statutes to disrupt harm groups online, noting that there certainly are circumstances where individuals can commit violations of domestic anti-terrorism statutes through their Internet activity alone.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Internet is a platform like any other, where virtually any kind of crime that can be committed in the real world can also be committed online,&#8221; he said. &#8220;That doesn&#8217;t mean all misuse of computers fits within the statutory definition of terrorism.&#8221;</p>
<p>The RCMP&#8217;s <a href="https://www.rcmp-grc.gc.ca/en/news/2024/rcmp-reminds-canadians-violent-online-groups-targeting-youth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">advisory on sexual extortion of minors over the Internet</a> lists a number of potential warning signs that teens may exhibit if they become entangled in these harm groups. The FBI <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/scams-and-safety/common-frauds-and-scams/sextortion/financially-motivated-sextortion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">urges</a> anyone who believes their child or someone they know is being exploited to contact their local FBI field office, call 1-800-CALL-FBI, or report it online at <a href="https://tips.fbi.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tips.fbi.gov.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bug Left Some Windows PCs Dangerously Unpatched</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/bug-left-some-windows-pcs-dangerously-unpatched/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/bug-left-some-windows-pcs-dangerously-unpatched/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 21:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38217]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38226]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-43491]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kev Breen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark of the web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patch Tuesday September 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp. today released updates to fix at least 79 security vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and related software, including multiple flaws that are already showing up in active attacks. Microsoft also corrected a critical bug that has caused some Windows 10 PCs to remain dangerously unpatched against actively exploited vulnerabilities for several months this year.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft Corp.</strong> today released updates to fix at least 79 security vulnerabilities in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and related software, including multiple flaws that are already showing up in active attacks. Microsoft also corrected a critical bug that has caused some <strong>Windows 10</strong> PCs to remain dangerously unpatched against actively exploited vulnerabilities for several months this year.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-60331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png 923w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>By far the most curious security weakness Microsoft disclosed today has the snappy name of <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2024-43491" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-43491</a>, which Microsoft says is a vulnerability that led to the rolling back of fixes for some vulnerabilities affecting &#8220;optional components&#8221; on certain Windows 10 systems produced in 2015. Those include Windows 10 systems that installed the monthly security update for Windows released in March 2024, or other updates released until August 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Satnam Narang</strong>, senior staff research engineer at <strong>Tenable</strong>, said that while the phrase &#8220;exploitation detected&#8221; in a Microsoft advisory normally implies the flaw is being exploited by cybercriminals, it appears labeled this way with CVE-2024-43491 because the rollback of fixes reintroduced vulnerabilities that were previously know to be exploited.</p>
<p>&#8220;To correct this issue, users need to apply both the September 2024 Servicing Stack Update and the September 2024 Windows Security Updates,&#8221; Narang said.</p>
<p><strong>Kev Breen</strong>, senior director of threat research at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong>, said the root cause of CVE-2024-43491 is that on specific versions of Windows 10, the build version numbers that are checked by the update service were not properly handled in the code.</p>
<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2024-43491" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes from Microsoft</a> say that the &#8216;build version numbers crossed into a range that triggered a code defect&#8217;,&#8221; Breen said. &#8220;The short version is that some versions of Windows 10 with optional components enabled was left in a vulnerable state.&#8221;<span id="more-68633"></span></p>
<p>Zero Day #1 this month is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2024-38226" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38226</a>, and it concerns a weakness in <strong>Microsoft Publisher</strong>, a standalone application included in some versions of <strong>Microsoft Office</strong>. This flaw lets attackers bypass Microsoft&#8217;s &#8220;<strong>Mark of the Web</strong>,&#8221; a Windows security feature that marks files downloaded from the Internet as potentially unsafe.</p>
<p>Zero Day #2 is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2024-38217" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38217</a>, also a Mark of the Web bypass affecting Office. Both zero-day flaws rely on the target opening a booby-trapped Office file.</p>
<p>Security firm <strong>Rapid7</strong> notes that CVE-2024-38217 has been publicly disclosed via <a href="https://www.elastic.co/security-labs/dismantling-smart-app-control" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an extensive write-up</a>, with exploit code also available on GitHub.</p>
<p>According to Microsoft, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2024-38014" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38014</a>, an &#8220;elevation of privilege&#8221; bug in the Windows Installer, is also being actively exploited.</p>
<p>June&#8217;s coverage of Microsoft Patch Tuesday was titled &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/patch-tuesday-june-2024-recall-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Recall Edition</a>,&#8221; because the big news then was that Microsoft was facing a torrent of criticism from privacy and security experts over &#8220;<strong>Recall</strong>,&#8221; a new artificial intelligence (AI) feature of Redmond’s flagship Copilot+ PCs that constantly takes screenshots of whatever users are doing on their computers.</p>
<p>At the time, Microsoft responded by suggesting Recall would no longer be enabled by default. But last week, the software giant clarified that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/2/24233992/microsoft-recall-windows-11-uninstall-feature-bug" target="_blank" rel="noopener">what it really meant</a> was that the ability to disable Recall was a bug/feature in the preview version of Copilot+ that will not be available to Windows customers going forward. Translation: New versions of Windows are shipping with Recall deeply embedded in the operating system.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s pretty rich that Microsoft, which already collects an insane amount of information from its customers on a near constant basis, is calling the Recall removal feature a bug, while treating Recall as a desirable feature. Because from where I sit, Recall is a feature nobody asked for that turns Windows into a bug (of the surveillance variety).</p>
<p>When Redmond first responded to critics about Recall, they noted that Recall snapshots never leave the user’s system, and that even if attackers managed to hack a Copilot+ PC they would not be able to exfiltrate on-device Recall data.</p>
<p>But that claim rang hollow after former Microsoft threat analyst <strong>Kevin Beaumont</strong> <a href="https://doublepulsar.com/recall-stealing-everything-youve-ever-typed-or-viewed-on-your-own-windows-pc-is-now-possible-da3e12e9465e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">detailed on his blog</a> how any user on the system (even a non-administrator) can export Recall data, which is just stored in an SQLite database locally.</p>
<p>As it is apt to do on Microsoft Patch Tuesday, Adobe has <a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/security.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released updates</a> to fix security vulnerabilities in a range of products, including <strong>Reader</strong> and <strong>Acrobat</strong>, <strong>After Effects</strong>, <strong>Premiere Pro</strong>, <strong>Illustrator</strong>, <strong>ColdFusion</strong>, <strong>Adobe Audition</strong>, and <strong>Photoshop</strong>. Adobe says it is not aware of any exploits in the wild for any of the issues addressed in its updates.</p>
<p>Seeking a more detailed breakdown of the patches released by Microsoft today? Check out the SANS Internet Storm Center&#8217;s <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft+September+2024+Patch+Tuesday/31254/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thorough list</a>. People responsible for administering many systems in an enterprise environment would do well to keep an eye on <a href="https://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskWoody.com</a>, which often has the skinny on any wonky Windows patches that may be causing problems for some users.</p>
<p>As always, if you experience any issues applying this month&#8217;s patch batch, consider dropping a note in the comments here about it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/bug-left-some-windows-pcs-dangerously-unpatched/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sextortion Scams Now Include Photos of Your Home</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/sextortion-scams-now-include-photos-of-your-home/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/sextortion-scams-now-include-photos-of-your-home/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sextortion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An old but persistent email scam known as "sextortion" has a new personalized touch: The missives, which claim that malware has captured webcam footage of recipients pleasuring themselves, now include a photo of the target's home in a bid to make threats about publishing the videos more frightening and convincing.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An old but persistent email scam known as &#8220;<strong>sextortion</strong>&#8221; has a new personalized touch: The missives, which claim that malware has captured webcam footage of recipients pleasuring themselves, now include a photo of the target&#8217;s home in a bid to make threats about publishing the videos more frightening and convincing.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-44412" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/sextortion.png" alt="" width="750" height="134" /></p>
<p>This week, several readers reported receiving sextortion emails that addressed them by name and included images of their street or front yard that were apparently lifted from an online mapping application such as <strong>Google Maps</strong>.</p>
<p>The message purports to have been sent from a hacker who’s compromised your computer and used your webcam to record a video of you while you were watching porn. The missive threatens to release the video to all of your contacts unless you pay a Bitcoin ransom. In this case, the demand is just shy of $2,000, payable by scanning a QR code embedded in the email.</p>
<p>Following a salutation that includes the recipient&#8217;s full name, the start of the message reads, &#8220;Is visiting [recipient&#8217;s street address] a more convenient way to contact if you don&#8217;t take action. Nice location btw.&#8221; Below that is the photo of the recipient&#8217;s street address.</p>
<div id="attachment_68587" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68587" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68587" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sextortion-maps.png" alt="" width="748" height="677" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sextortion-maps.png 996w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sextortion-maps-768x695.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sextortion-maps-782x707.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68587" class="wp-caption-text">A semi-redacted screenshot of a newish sextortion scam that includes a photo of the target&#8217;s front yard.</p></div>
<p>The message tells people they have 24 hours to pay up, or else their embarrassing videos will be released to all of their contacts, friends and family members.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t even think about replying to this, it&#8217;s pointless,&#8221; the message concludes. &#8220;I don&#8217;t make mistakes, [recipient&#8217;s name]. If I notice that you&#8217;ve shared or discussed this email with someone else, your shitty video will instantly start getting sent to your contacts.&#8221;</p>
<p>The remaining sections of the two-page sextortion message (which arrives as a PDF attachment) are fairly formulaic and include thematic elements seen in most previous sextortion waves. Those include claims that the extortionist has installed malware on your computer (in this case the scammer claims the spyware is called &#8220;Pegasus,&#8221; and that they are watching everything you do on your machine).</p>
<p>Previous innovations in sextortion customization involved sending emails that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/sextortion-scam-uses-recipients-hacked-passwords/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">included at least one password they had previously used</a> at an account online that was tied to their email address. <span id="more-68585"></span></p>
<div class="entry-content">
<p>Sextortion — even semi-automated scams like this one with no actual physical leverage to backstop the extortion demand — is a serious crime that can lead to devastating consequences for victims. Sextortion occurs when someone threatens to distribute your private and sensitive material if you don’t provide them with images of a sexual nature, sexual favors, or money.</p>
<p>According to the FBI, here are some things you can do to avoid becoming a victim:</p>
<p>-Never send compromising images of yourself to anyone, no matter who they are — or who they say they are.<br />
-Don’t open attachments from people you don’t know, and be wary of opening attachments even from those you do know.<br />
-Turn off [and/or cover] any web cameras when you are not using them.</p>
<p>The FBI says in many sextortion cases, the perpetrator is an adult pretending to be a teenager, and you are just one of the many victims being targeted by the same person. If you believe you’re a victim of sextortion, or know someone else who is, the FBI wants to hear from you: Contact your local FBI office (or toll-free at 1-800-CALL-FBI).</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/sextortion-scams-now-include-photos-of-your-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Owners of 1-Time Passcode Theft Service Plead Guilty</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/owners-of-1-time-passcode-theft-service-plead-guilty/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/owners-of-1-time-passcode-theft-service-plead-guilty/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 16:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aza Siddeeque]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Callum Picari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Crime Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otp agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RaidForums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMSRanger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vijayasidhurshan Vijayanathan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three men in the United Kingdom have pleaded guilty to operating otp[.]agency, a once popular online service that helped attackers intercept the one-time passcodes (OTPs) that many websites require as a second authentication factor in addition to passwords.

Launched in November 2019, OTP Agency was a service for intercepting one-time passwords needed to log in to various websites. Scammers would enter the target’s phone number and name, and the service would initiate an automated phone call to the target that alerts them about unauthorized activity on their account.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three men in the United Kingdom have pleaded guilty to operating <strong>otp[.]agency</strong>, a once popular online service that helped attackers intercept the one-time passcodes (OTPs) that many websites require as a second authentication factor in addition to passwords.</p>
<p>Launched in November 2019, OTP Agency was a service for intercepting one-time passcodes needed to log in to various websites. Scammers who had already stolen someone&#8217;s bank account credentials could enter the target’s phone number and name, and the service would initiate an automated phone call to the target that warned them about unauthorized activity on their account.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/45GsKWyF63U?si=WcCChUe4gFLTpnxO" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>The call would prompt the target to enter a one-time passcode that was sent to the user via SMS when the thieves attempted to log in. Any codes shared by the target were then relayed to the scammer’s user panel at the OTP Agency website.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.nationalcrimeagency.gov.uk/news/website-operators-promised-fraudsters-profit-within-minutes-if-they-subscribed-to-illegal-service" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> published Aug. 30 by the U.K.&#8217;s <strong>National Crime Agency</strong> (NCA) said three men pleaded guilty to running OTP Agency: <strong>Callum Picari</strong>, 22, from Hornchurch, Essex; <strong>Vijayasidhurshan Vijayanathan</strong>, 21, from Aylesbury, Buckinghamshire; and <strong>Aza Siddeeque</strong>, 19, from Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity profiled OTP Agency in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/02/u-k-arrest-in-sms-bandits-phishing-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a February 2021 story</a> about arrests tied to another phishing-related service based in the U.K. Someone claiming to represent OTP Agency then posted several comments on the piece, wherein <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/otp-support.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they claimed</a> the story was libelous and that they were a legitimate anti-fraud service. However, the service&#8217;s Telegram channel clearly showed its proprietors had built OTP Agency with one purpose in mind: To help their customers take over online accounts.</p>
<p>Within hours of that publication, OTP Agency shuttered its website and announced it was closing up shop and purging its user database. The NCA said the February 2021 story prompted a panicked message exchange between Picari and Vijayanathan:</p>
<blockquote><p>Picari said: bro we are in big trouble… U will get me bagged… Bro delete the chat</p>
<p>Vijayanathan: Are you sure</p>
<p>Picari: So much evidence in there</p>
<p>Vijayanathan: Are you 100% sure</p>
<p>Picari: It’s so incriminating&#8230;Take a look and search &#8216;fraud&#8217;&#8230;Just think of all the evidence&#8230;that we cba to find&#8230;in the OTP chat&#8230;they will find</p>
<p>Vijayanathan: Exactly so if we just shut EVERYTHING down</p>
<p>Picari: They went to our first ever msg&#8230;We look incriminating&#8230;if we shut down&#8230;I say delete the chat&#8230;Our chat is Fraud 100%</p>
<p>Vijayanathan : Everyone with a brain will tell you stop it here and move on</p>
<p>Picari: Just because we close it doesn’t mean we didn’t do it&#8230;But deleting our chat&#8230;Will f*^k their investigations&#8230;There’s nothing fraudulent on the site</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite deleting its Telegram channel, OTP Agency evidently found it difficult to walk away from its customers (and/or the money). Instead of shutting down as Vijayanathan wisely advised, just a few days later OTP Agency was communicating with customers <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/otp-support.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on a new Telegram channel</a>, offering a new login page and assuring existing customers that their usernames, passwords and balances would remain the same.</p>
<div id="attachment_68562" style="width: 785px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68562" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-68562" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/optagency-reborn.png" alt="" width="775" height="632" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/optagency-reborn.png 775w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/optagency-reborn-768x626.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 775px) 100vw, 775px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68562" class="wp-caption-text">OTP Agency, immediately after their initial shutdown, telling customers their existing logins will still work.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-68557"></span>But that revival would be short-lived. The NCA said the site was taken offline less than a month later when the trio were arrested. NCA investigators said more than 12,500 people were targeted by OTP Agency users during the 18 months the service was active.</p>
<p>Picari was the owner, developer and main beneficiary of the service, and his personal information and ownership of OTP Agency was revealed in February 2020 in a &#8220;dox&#8221; posted to the now-defunct English-language cybercrime forum <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Raidforums</a>. The NCA said it began investigating the service in June 2020.</p>
<div id="attachment_68565" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68565" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68565" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/otpa-mugshots.png" alt="" width="748" height="440" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/otpa-mugshots.png 775w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/otpa-mugshots-768x452.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68565" class="wp-caption-text">The OTP Agency operators who pleaded guilty to running the service; Aza Siddeeque, Callum Picari, and Vijayasidhurshan Vijayanathan.</p></div>
<p>OTP Agency might be gone, but several other similar OTP interception services are still in operation and accepting new customers, including a long-running service <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/the-rise-of-one-time-password-interception-bots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KrebsOnSecurity profiled in September 2021</a> called <strong>SMSRanger</strong>. More on SMSRanger in an upcoming post.</p>
<p>Text messages, emails and phone calls warning recipients about potential fraud are some of the most common scam lures. If someone (or something) calls saying they&#8217;re from your bank, or asks you to provide any personal or financial information, <em>do not respond</em>.  Just hang up, full stop.</p>
<p>If the call has you worried about the security and integrity of your account, check the account status online, or call your financial institution — ideally using a phone number that came from the bank’s Web site or from the back of your payment card.</p>
<p>Further reading: <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">When in Doubt, Hang Up, Look Up, and Call Back</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/owners-of-1-time-passcode-theft-service-plead-guilty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Get-Out-The-Vote Efforts Look Like Phishing</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/when-get-out-the-vote-efforts-look-like-phishing/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/when-get-out-the-vote-efforts-look-like-phishing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 23:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[all-vote.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Debra Cleaver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DomainTools.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movement Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vote America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[votewin.org]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WDIV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoni Landau]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Multiple media reports this week warned Americans to be on guard against a new phishing scam that arrives in a text message informing recipients they are not yet registered to vote. A bit of digging reveals the missives were sent by a California political consulting firm as part of a well-meaning but potentially counterproductive get-out-the-vote effort that had all the hallmarks of a phishing campaign.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Multiple media reports this week warned Americans to be on guard against a new phishing scam that arrives in a text message informing recipients they are not yet registered to vote. A bit of digging reveals the missives were sent by a California political consulting firm as part of a well-meaning but potentially counterproductive get-out-the-vote effort that had all the hallmarks of a phishing campaign.</p>
<div id="attachment_68534" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68534" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68534" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wdiv-sms.png" alt="" width="749" height="413" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wdiv-sms.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wdiv-sms-768x423.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wdiv-sms-782x431.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68534" class="wp-caption-text">Image: WDIV Detroit on Youtube.</p></div>
<p>On Aug. 27, the local Channel 4 affiliate <strong>WDIV</strong> in Detroit <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXkKZ4T25h0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned</a> about a new SMS message wave that they said could prevent registered voters from casting their ballot. The story didn&#8217;t explain how or why the scam could block eligible voters from casting ballots, but it did show one of the related text messages, which linked to the site <strong>all-vote.com</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have you in our records as not registered to vote,&#8221; the unbidden SMS advised. &#8220;Check your registration status &amp; register in 2 minutes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Similar warnings came from <a href="https://www.abc15.com/news/political/elections/spam-or-real-unsolicited-text-messages-say-you-arent-registered-to-vote" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an ABC station in Arizona</a>, and from <a href="https://www.wgal.com/article/south-central-pennsylvania-voters-question-text-message-about-registration-status/61960563" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an NBC affiliate in Pennsylvania</a>, where election officials <a href="https://co.lancaster.pa.us/CivicAlerts.aspx?AID=2204" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just issued an alert</a> to be on the lookout for scam messages coming from all-vote.com. Some people interviewed who received the messages said they figured it was a scam because they knew for a fact they <em>were</em> registered to vote in their state. WDIV even interviewed a seventh-grader from Canada who said he also got the SMS saying he wasn&#8217;t registered to vote.</p>
<p>Someone trying to determine whether all-vote.com was legitimate might visit the main URL first (as opposed to just clicking the link in the SMS) to find out more about the organization. But visiting all-vote.com directly presents one with a login page to an online service called bl.ink. <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> finds all-vote.com was registered on July 10, 2024. Red flag #1.</p>
<div id="attachment_68538" style="width: 268px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68538" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68538" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/winvotecheckstatus.png" alt="" width="258" height="406" /><p id="caption-attachment-68538" class="wp-caption-text">The information requested from people who visited votewin.org via the SMS campaign.</p></div>
<p>Another version of this SMS campaign told recipients to check their voter status at a site called <strong>votewin.org</strong>, which DomainTools says was registered July 9, 2024. There is little information about who runs votewin.org on its website, and the contact page leads to generic contact form. Red Flag #2.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, Votewin.org asks visitors to supply their name, address, email address, date of birth, mobile phone number, while pre-checking options to sign the visitor up for more notifications. Big Red Flag #3.</p>
<p>Votewin.org&#8217;s Terms of Service referenced a California-based voter engagement platform called <strong>VoteAmerica LLC.</strong> The same voter registration query form advertised in the SMS messages is available if one clicks the &#8220;check your registration status&#8221; link on voteamerica.org.</p>
<p>VoteAmerica founder <strong>Debra Cleaver</strong> told KrebsOnSecurity the entity responsible for the SMS campaigns telling people they weren&#8217;t registered is <strong>Movement Labs</strong>, a political consulting firm in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Cleaver said her office had received several inquiries about the messages, which violate a key tenet of election outreach: Never tell the recipient what their voter status may be.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s one of the worst practices,&#8221; Cleaver said. &#8220;You never tell someone what the voter file says because voter files are not reliable, and are often out of date.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reached via email, Movement Labs founder <strong>Yoni Landau</strong> said the SMS campaigns targeted &#8220;underrepresented groups in the electorate, young people, folks who are moving, low income households and the like, who are unregistered in our databases, with the intent to help them register to vote.&#8221;</p>
<p>Landau said filling out the form on Votewin.org merely checks to see if the visitor is registered to vote in their state, and then attempts to help them register if not.</p>
<p>&#8220;We understand that many people are jarred by the messages &#8211; we tested hundreds of variations of messages and found that these had the largest impact on someone&#8217;s likelihood to register,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I&#8217;m deeply sorry for anyone that may have gotten the message in error, who is registered to vote, and we&#8217;re looking into our content now to see if there are any variations that might be less certain but still as effective in generating new legal registrations.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cleaver said Movement Labs&#8217; SMS campaign may have been incompetent, but it wasn&#8217;t malicious.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you work in voter mobilization, it&#8217;s not enough to want to do good, you actually need to be good,&#8221; she said. &#8220;At the end of the day the end result of incompetence and maliciousness is the same: increased chaos, reduced voter turnout, and long-term harm to our democracy.&#8221;</p>
<p>To register to vote or to update your voter registration, visit <a href="https://www.vote.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vote.gov</a> and select your state or region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/when-get-out-the-vote-efforts-look-like-phishing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New 0-Day Attacks Linked to China&#8217;s &#8216;Volt Typhoon&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/new-0-day-attacks-linked-to-chinas-volt-typhoon/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/new-0-day-attacks-linked-to-chinas-volt-typhoon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things (IoT)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Lotus Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bronze Silhouette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christopher Wray]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-39717]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insidious Taurus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KV-botnet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumen Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Horka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national security agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ryan English]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Versa Director 22.1.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volt Typhoon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Malicious hackers are exploiting a zero-day vulnerability in Versa Director, a software product used by many Internet and IT service providers. Researchers believe the activity is linked to Volt Typhoon, a Chinese cyber espionage group focused on infiltrating critical U.S. networks and laying the groundwork for the ability to disrupt communications between the United States and Asia during any future armed conflict with China.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Malicious hackers are exploiting a zero-day vulnerability in <strong>Versa Director</strong>, a software product used by many Internet and IT service providers. Researchers believe the activity is linked to <strong>Volt Typhoon</strong>, a Chinese cyber espionage group focused on infiltrating critical U.S. networks and laying the groundwork for the ability to disrupt communications between the United States and Asia during any future armed conflict with China.</p>
<div id="attachment_68507" style="width: 850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68507" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-68507" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/ss-dissolvingsphere.png" alt="" width="840" height="508" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/ss-dissolvingsphere.png 840w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/ss-dissolvingsphere-768x464.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/ss-dissolvingsphere-782x473.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68507" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock.com</p></div>
<p>Versa Director systems are primarily used by Internet service providers (ISPs), as well as managed service providers (MSPs) that cater to the IT needs of many small to mid-sized businesses simultaneously. In <a href="https://versa-networks.com/blog/versa-security-bulletin-update-on-cve-2024-39717-versa-director-dangerous-file-type-upload-vulnerability/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a security advisory</a> published Aug. 26, Versa urged customers to deploy a patch for the vulnerability (<a href="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2024-39717" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-39717</a>), which the company said is fixed in <em>Versa Director 22.1.4</em> or later.</p>
<p>Versa said the weakness allows attackers to upload a file of their choosing to vulnerable systems. The advisory placed much of the blame on Versa customers who &#8220;failed to implement system hardening and firewall guidelines&#8230;leaving a management port exposed on the internet that provided the threat actors with initial access.&#8221;</p>
<p>Versa&#8217;s advisory doesn&#8217;t say how it learned of the zero-day flaw, but its vulnerability listing at mitre.org acknowledges &#8220;there are reports of others based on backbone telemetry observations of a 3rd party provider, however these are unconfirmed to date.&#8221;</p>
<p>Those third-party reports came in late June 2024 from <strong>Michael Horka</strong>, senior lead information security engineer at <strong>Black Lotus Labs</strong>, the security research arm of <strong>Lumen Technologies</strong>, which operates one of the global Internet&#8217;s largest backbones.</p>
<p>In an interview with KrebsOnSecurity, Horka said Black Lotus Labs identified a web-based backdoor on Versa Director systems belonging to four U.S. victims and one non-U.S. victim in the ISP and MSP sectors, with the earliest known exploit activity occurring at a U.S. ISP on June 12, 2024.</p>
<p>&#8220;This makes Versa Director a lucrative target for advanced persistent threat (APT) actors who would want to view or control network infrastructure at scale, or pivot into additional (or downstream) networks of interest,&#8221; Horka <a href="https://blog.lumen.com/taking-the-crossroads-the-versa-director-zero-day-exploitation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> in a blog post published today.</p>
<p>Black Lotus Labs said it assessed with &#8220;medium&#8221; confidence that Volt Typhoon was responsible for the compromises, noting the intrusions bear the hallmarks of the Chinese state-sponsored espionage group &#8212; including zero-day attacks targeting IT infrastructure providers, and Java-based backdoors that run in memory only.</p>
<p>In May 2023, the <strong>National Security Agency</strong> (NSA), the <strong>Federal Bureau of Investigation</strong> (FBI), and the <strong>Cybersecurity Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA) issued <a href="https://media.defense.gov/2023/May/24/2003229517/-1/-1/0/CSA_Living_off_the_Land.PDF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a joint warning</a> (PDF) about Volt Typhoon, also known as &#8220;<strong>Bronze Silhouette</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Insidious Taurus</strong>,&#8221; which described how the group uses small office/home office (SOHO) network devices to hide their activity.</p>
<p>In early December 2023, Black Lotus Labs <a href="https://blog.lumen.com/routers-roasting-on-an-open-firewall-the-kv-botnet-investigation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published its findings</a> on &#8220;<strong>KV-botnet</strong>,&#8221; thousands of compromised SOHO routers that were chained together to form a covert data transfer network supporting various Chinese state-sponsored hacking groups, including Volt Typhoon.</p>
<p>In January 2024, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> disclosed the FBI had <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/us-government-disrupts-botnet-peoples-republic-china-used-conceal-hacking-critical" target="_blank" rel="noopener">executed a court-authorized takedown</a> of the KV-botnet shortly before Black Lotus Labs released its December report.<span id="more-68493"></span></p>
<p>In February 2024, CISA again joined the FBI and NSA in <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa24-038a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warning</a> Volt Typhoon had compromised the IT environments of multiple critical infrastructure organizations &#8212; primarily in communications, energy, transportation systems, and water and wastewater sectors &#8212; in the continental and non-continental United States and its territories, including Guam.</p>
<p>&#8220;Volt Typhoon’s choice of targets and pattern of behavior is not consistent with traditional cyber espionage or intelligence gathering operations, and the U.S. authoring agencies assess with high confidence that Volt Typhoon actors are pre-positioning themselves on IT networks to enable lateral movement to OT [operational technology] assets to disrupt functions,&#8221; that alert warned.</p>
<p>In a speech at Vanderbilt University in April, FBI Director <strong>Christopher Wray</strong> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/fbi-says-chinese-hackers-preparing-attack-us-infrastructure-2024-04-18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> China is developing the &#8220;ability to physically wreak havoc on our critical infrastructure at a time of its choosing,&#8221; and that China&#8217;s plan is to &#8220;land blows against civilian infrastructure to try to induce panic.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Ryan English</strong>, an information security engineer at Lumen, said it&#8217;s disappointing his employer didn&#8217;t at least garner an honorable mention in Versa&#8217;s security advisory. But he said he&#8217;s glad there are now a lot fewer Versa systems exposed to this attack.</p>
<p>&#8220;Lumen has for the last nine weeks been very intimate with their leadership with the goal in mind of helping them mitigate this,&#8221; English said. &#8220;We&#8217;ve given them everything we could along the way, so it kind of sucks being referenced just as a third party.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/new-0-day-attacks-linked-to-chinas-volt-typhoon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Local Networks Go Global When Domain Names Collide</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Active Directory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andorra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNS name devolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memphis Real-Time Crime Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memrtcc.ad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Barlow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike O'Connor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namespace collision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Proxy Auto-Discovery Protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpad.ad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpad.dk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The proliferation of new top-level domains (TLDs) has exacerbated a well-known security weakness: Many organizations set up their internal Microsoft authentication systems years ago using domain names in TLDs that didn't exist at the time. Meaning, they are continuously sending their Windows usernames and passwords to domain names they do not control and which are freely available for anyone to register. Here's a look at one security researcher's efforts to map and shrink the size of this insidious problem.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The proliferation of new top-level domains (TLDs) has exacerbated a well-known security weakness: Many organizations set up their internal Microsoft authentication systems years ago using domain names in TLDs that didn&#8217;t exist at the time. Meaning, they are continuously sending their Windows usernames and passwords to domain names they do not control and which are freely available for anyone to register. Here&#8217;s a look at one security researcher&#8217;s efforts to map and shrink the size of this insidious problem.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-68467" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/tld-cloud.png" alt="" width="746" height="405" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/tld-cloud.png 1055w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/tld-cloud-768x417.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/tld-cloud-782x425.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/tld-cloud-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 746px) 100vw, 746px" /></p>
<p>At issue is a well-known security and privacy threat called “<a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3480799/icann-seeks-to-tackle-dns-namespace-collision-risks.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">namespace collision</a>,” a situation where domain names intended to be used exclusively on an internal company network end up overlapping with domains that can resolve normally on the open Internet.</p>
<p>Windows computers on a private corporate network validate other things on that network using a Microsoft innovation called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_Directory" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Active Directory</a>, which is the umbrella term for a broad range of identity-related services in Windows environments. A core part of the way these things find each other involves a Windows feature called “<a href="https://www.itprotoday.com/security/whats-dns-name-devolution" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DNS name devolution</a>,” a kind of network shorthand that makes it easier to find other computers or servers without having to specify a full, legitimate domain name for those resources.</p>
<p>Consider the hypothetical private network internalnetwork.example.com: When an employee on this network wishes to access a shared drive called “drive1,” there’s no need to type “drive1.internalnetwork.example.com” into Windows Explorer; entering “\\drive1\” alone will suffice, and Windows takes care of the rest.</p>
<p>But problems can arise when an organization has built their Active Directory network on top of a domain they don&#8217;t own or control. While that may sound like a bonkers way to design a corporate authentication system, keep in mind that many organizations built their networks long before the introduction of hundreds of new top-level domains (TLDs), like .network, .inc, and .llc.</p>
<p>For example, a company in 2005 builds their Microsoft Active Directory service around the domain <strong>company.llc</strong>, perhaps reasoning that since .llc wasn&#8217;t even a routable TLD, the domain would simply fail to resolve if the organization&#8217;s Windows computers were ever used outside of its local network.</p>
<p>Alas, in 2018, the .llc TLD was born and began selling domains. From then on, anyone who registered company.llc would be able to passively intercept that organization&#8217;s Microsoft Windows credentials, or actively modify those connections in some way &#8212; such as redirecting them somewhere malicious.</p>
<p><strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, founder of the security consultancy <a href="https://www.seralys.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seralys</a>, is one of several researchers seeking to chart the size of the namespace collision problem. As a professional penetration tester, Caturegli has long exploited these collisions to attack specific targets that were paying to have their cyber defenses probed. But over the past year, Caturegli has been gradually mapping this vulnerability across the Internet by looking for clues that appear in self-signed security certificates (e.g. SSL/TLS certs).</p>
<p>Caturegli has been scanning the open Internet for self-signed certificates referencing domains in a variety of TLDs likely to appeal to businesses, including <strong>.ad, .associates, .center, .cloud, .consulting, .dev, .digital, .domains, .email, .global, .gmbh, .group, .holdings, .host, .inc, .institute, .international, .it, .llc, .ltd, .management, .ms, .name, .network, .security, .services, .site, .srl, .support, .systems, .tech, .university, .win </strong>and<strong> .zone</strong>, among others.</p>
<p>Seralys found certificates referencing more than 9,000 distinct domains across those TLDs. Their analysis determined many TLDs had far more exposed domains than others, and that about 20 percent of the domains they found ending .ad, .cloud and .group remain unregistered.</p>
<p>&#8220;The scale of the issue seems bigger than I initially anticipated,&#8221; Caturegli said in an interview with KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;And while doing my research, I have also identified government entities (foreign and domestic), critical infrastructures, etc. that have such misconfigured assets.&#8221;</p>
<h2>REAL-TIME CRIME</h2>
<p>Some of the above-listed TLDs are not new and correspond to country-code TLDs, like <strong>.it</strong> for Italy, and <strong>.ad</strong>, the country-code TLD for the tiny nation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andorra" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andorra</a>. Caturegli said many organizations no doubt viewed a domain ending in .ad as a convenient shorthand for an internal <strong>A</strong>ctive <strong>D</strong>irectory setup, while being unaware or unworried that someone could actually register such a domain and intercept all of their Windows credentials and any unencrypted traffic.</p>
<p>When Caturegli discovered an encryption certificate being actively used for the domain <strong>memrtcc.ad, </strong>the domain was still available for registration. He then learned the .ad registry requires prospective customers to show a valid trademark for a domain before it can be registered.</p>
<p>Undeterred, Caturegli found a domain registrar that would sell him the domain for $160, and handle the trademark registration for another $500 (on subsequent .ad registrations, he located a company in Andorra that could process the trademark application for half that amount).</p>
<p>Caturegli said that immediately after setting up a DNS server for memrtcc.ad, he began receiving a flood of communications from hundreds of Microsoft Windows computers trying to authenticate to the domain. Each request contained a username and a hashed Windows password, and upon searching the usernames online Caturegli concluded they all belonged to police officers in Memphis, Tenn.</p>
<p>&#8220;It looks like all of the police cars there have a laptop in the cars, and they&#8217;re all attached to this memrtcc.ad domain that I now own,&#8221; Caturegli said, noting wryly that &#8220;memrtcc&#8221; stands for &#8220;<strong>Memphis Real-Time Crime Center</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Caturegli said setting up an email server record for memrtcc.ad caused him to begin receiving automated messages from the police department&#8217;s IT help desk, including trouble tickets regarding the city&#8217;s Okta authentication system.</p>
<p><strong>Mike Barlow</strong>, information security manager for the City of Memphis, confirmed the Memphis Police&#8217;s systems were sharing their Microsoft Windows credentials with the domain, and that the city was working with Caturegli to have the domain transferred to them.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working with the Memphis Police Department to at least somewhat mitigate the issue in the meantime,&#8221; Barlow said.</p>
<p>Domain administrators have long been encouraged to use <strong>.local</strong> for internal domain names, because this TLD is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.local" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reserved for use by local networks</a> and cannot be routed over the open Internet. However, Caturegli said many organizations seem to have missed that memo and gotten things backwards &#8212; setting up their internal Active Directory structure around the perfectly routable domain <strong>local.ad</strong>.</p>
<p>Caturegli said he knows this because he &#8220;defensively&#8221; registered local.ad, which he said is currently used by multiple large organizations for Active Directory setups &#8212; including a European mobile phone provider, and the <strong>City of Newcastle</strong> in the United Kingdom.<span id="more-68352"></span></p>
<h2>ONE WPAD TO RULE THEM ALL</h2>
<p>Caturegli said he has now defensively registered a number of domains ending in .ad, such as internal.ad and schema.ad. But perhaps the most dangerous domain in his stable is <strong>wpad.ad</strong>. WPAD stands for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Proxy_Auto-Discovery_Protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Web Proxy Auto-Discovery Protocol</a>, which is an ancient, on-by-default feature built into every version of Microsoft Windows that was designed to make it simpler for Windows computers to automatically find and download any proxy settings required by the local network.</p>
<p>Trouble is, any organization that chose a .ad domain they don&#8217;t own for their Active Directory setup will have a whole bunch of Microsoft systems constantly trying to reach out to wpad.ad if those machines have proxy automated detection enabled.</p>
<p>Security researchers have been beating up on WPAD for more than two decades now, warning time and again how it can be abused for nefarious ends. At this year&#8217;s DEF CON security conference in Las Vegas, for example, a researcher <a href="https://defcon.org/html/defcon-32/dc-32-speakers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">showed</a> what happened after they registered the domain <strong>wpad.dk</strong>: Immediately after switching on the domain, they received a flood of WPAD requests from Microsoft Windows systems in Denmark that had namespace collisions in their Active Directory environments.</p>
<div id="attachment_68468" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68468" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68468" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wpad-defcon.png" alt="" width="748" height="314" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wpad-defcon.png 884w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wpad-defcon-768x322.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/wpad-defcon-782x328.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68468" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Defcon.org.</p></div>
<p>For his part, Caturegli set up a server on wpad.ad to resolve and record the Internet address of any Windows systems trying to reach <strong>Microsoft Sharepoint</strong> servers, and saw that over one week it received more than 140,000 hits from hosts around the world attempting to connect.</p>
<p>The fundamental problem with WPAD is the same with Active Directory: Both are technologies originally designed to be used in closed, static, trusted office environments, and neither was built with today&#8217;s mobile devices or workforce in mind.</p>
<p>Probably one big reason organizations with potential namespace collision problems don&#8217;t fix them is that rebuilding one&#8217;s Active Directory infrastructure around a new domain name can be incredibly disruptive, costly, and risky, while the potential threat is considered comparatively low.</p>
<p>But Caturegli said ransomware gangs and other cybercrime groups could siphon huge volumes of Microsoft Windows credentials from quite a few companies with just a small up-front investment.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s an easy way to gain that initial access without even having to launch an actual attack,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You just wait for the misconfigured workstation to connect to you and send you their credentials.&#8221;</p>
<p>If we ever learn that cybercrime groups are using namespace collisions to launch ransomware attacks, nobody can say they weren&#8217;t warned. <strong>Mike O&#8217;Connor</strong>, an early domain name investor who registered a number of choice domains such as bar.com, place.com and television.com, warned loudly and often back in 2013 that then-pending plans to add more than 1,000 new TLDs would massively expand the number of namespace collisions.</p>
<p>Mr. O&#8217;Connor&#8217;s most famous domain is <strong>corp.com</strong>, because for several decades he <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/02/dangerous-domain-corp-com-goes-up-for-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">watched in horror</a> as hundreds of thousands of Microsoft PCs continuously blasted his domain with credentials from organizations that had set up their Active Directory environment around the domain corp.com.</p>
<p>It turned out that Microsoft had actually used corp.com as an example of how one might set up Active Directory in some editions of Windows NT. Worse, some of the traffic going to corp.com was coming from Microsoft&#8217;s internal networks, indicating some part of Microsoft&#8217;s own internal infrastructure was misconfigured. When O&#8217;Connor said he was ready to sell corp.com to the highest bidder in 2020, Microsoft <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/microsoft-buys-corp-com-so-bad-guys-cant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">agreed to buy the domain for an undisclosed amount</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;I kind of imagine this problem to be something like a town [that] knowingly built a water supply out of lead pipes, or vendors of those projects who knew but didn&#8217;t tell their customers,&#8221; O&#8217;Connor told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;This is not an inadvertent thing like Y2K where everybody was surprised by what happened. People knew and didn&#8217;t care.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Public Data Published Its Own Passwords</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/national-public-data-published-its-own-passwords/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/national-public-data-published-its-own-passwords/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlas Data Privacy Corp.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CreationNext]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Public Data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[npd.pentester.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[npdbreach.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salvatore Verini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USInfoSearch.com]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New details are emerging about a breach at National Public Data (NPD), a consumer data broker that recently spilled hundreds of millions of Americans' Social Security Numbers, addresses, and phone numbers online. KrebsOnSecurity has learned that another NPD data broker which shares access to the same consumer records inadvertently published the passwords to its back-end database in a file that was freely available for download from its homepage until today.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New details are emerging about a breach at <strong>National Public Data</strong> (NPD), a consumer data broker that recently spilled hundreds of millions of Americans&#8217; Social Security Numbers, addresses, and phone numbers online. KrebsOnSecurity has learned that another NPD data broker which shares access to the same consumer records inadvertently published the passwords to its back-end database in a file that was freely available from its homepage until today.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-68388" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata.png" alt="" width="748" height="201" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata.png 964w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-768x206.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-782x210.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></p>
<p>In April, a cybercriminal named <strong>USDoD</strong> began selling data stolen from NPD. In July, someone leaked what was taken, including the names, addresses, phone numbers and in some cases email addresses for more than 272 million people (including many who are now deceased).</p>
<p>NPD <a href="https://nationalpublicdata.com/Breach.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acknowledged the intrusion on Aug. 12</a>, saying it dates back to a security incident in December 2023. In an interview last week, USDoD blamed the July data leak on another malicious hacker who also had access to the company&#8217;s database, which they claimed has been floating around the underground since December 2023.</p>
<p>Following <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-com-hack-exposes-a-nations-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last week&#8217;s story on the breadth of the NPD breach</a>, a reader alerted KrebsOnSecurity that a sister NPD property &#8212; the background search service <strong>recordscheck.net</strong> &#8212; was hosting an archive that included the usernames and password for the site&#8217;s administrator.</p>
<p>A review of that archive, which was available from the Records Check website until just before publication this morning (August 19), shows it includes the source code and plain text usernames and passwords for different components of recordscheck.net, which is visually similar to nationalpublicdata.com and features identical login pages.</p>
<p>The exposed archive, which was named &#8220;<strong>members.zip</strong>,&#8221; indicates RecordsCheck users were all initially assigned the same six-character password and instructed to change it, but many did not.</p>
<p>According to the breach tracking service <a href="https://www.constella.ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Constella Intelligence</a>, the passwords included in the source code archive are identical to credentials exposed in previous data breaches that involved email accounts belonging to NPD&#8217;s founder, an <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm4701915/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">actor</a> and retired sheriff&#8217;s deputy from Florida named <strong>Salvatore &#8220;Sal&#8221; Verini</strong>.</p>
<p>Reached via email, Mr. Verini said the exposed archive (a .zip file) containing recordscheck.net credentials has been removed from the company&#8217;s website, and that the site is slated to cease operations &#8220;in the next week or so.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Regarding the zip, it has been removed but was an old version of the site with non-working code and passwords,&#8221; Verini told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;Regarding your question, it is an active investigation, in which we cannot comment on at this point. But once we can, we will [be] with you, as we follow your blog. Very informative.&#8221;</p>
<p>The leaked recordscheck.net source code indicates the website was created by a web development firm based in Lahore, Pakistan called <strong>creationnext.com</strong>, which did not return messages seeking comment. CreationNext.com&#8217;s homepage features a positive testimonial from Sal Verini.</p>
<div id="attachment_68433" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68433" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68433" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/verini-creationnext.png" alt="" width="750" height="513" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/verini-creationnext.png 1212w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/verini-creationnext-768x525.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/verini-creationnext-782x535.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68433" class="wp-caption-text">A testimonial from Sal Verini on the homepage of CreationNext, the Lahore, Pakistan-based web development firm that apparently designed NPD and RecordsCheck.</p></div>
<p>There are now several websites that have been stood up to help people learn if their SSN and other data was exposed in this breach. One is <a href="https://www.npdbreach.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">npdbreach.com</a>, a lookup page erected by <strong>Atlas Data Privacy Corp</strong>. Another lookup service is available at <a href="https://npd.pentester.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">npd.pentester.com</a>. Both sites show NPD had old and largely inaccurate data on Yours Truly. <span id="more-68428"></span></p>
<p>The best advice for those concerned about this breach is to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/09/credit-freezes-are-free-let-the-ice-age-begin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">freeze one’s credit file</a> at <a href="https://www.usa.gov/credit-freeze" target="_blank" rel="noopener">each of the major consumer reporting bureaus</a>. Having a freeze on your files makes it much harder for identity thieves to create new accounts in your name, and it limits who can view your credit information.</p>
<p>A freeze is a good idea because all of the information that ID thieves need to assume your identity is now broadly available from multiple sources, thanks to the multiplicity of data breaches we’ve seen involving SSN data and other key static data points about people.</p>
<div id="attachment_65685" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/usis-tg-names.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-65685" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-65685" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/usis-tg-names.png" alt="" width="300" height="376" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-65685" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshots of a Telegram-based ID theft service that was selling background reports using hacked law enforcement accounts at USInfoSearch.</p></div>
<p>There are numerous cybercriminal services that offer detailed background checks on consumers, including full SSNs. These services are powered by compromised accounts at data brokers that cater to private investigators and law enforcement officials, and some are now fully automated via Telegram instant message bots.</p>
<p>In November 2023, KrebsOnSecurity wrote about one such service, which was being powered by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/11/id-theft-service-resold-access-to-usinfosearch-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hacked accounts at the U.S. consumer data broker USInfoSearch.com</a>. This is notable because the leaked source code indicates Records Check pulled background reports on people by querying NPD&#8217;s database and records at USInfoSearch. KrebsOnSecurity sought comment from USInfoSearch and will update this story if they respond.</p>
<p>The point is, if you’re an American who hasn’t frozen their credit files and you haven’t yet experienced some form of new account fraud, the ID thieves probably just haven’t gotten around to you yet.</p>
<p>All Americans are also entitled to obtain a free copy of their credit report weekly from each of the three major credit bureaus. It used to be that consumers were allowed one free report from each of the bureaus annually, but in October 2023 the <strong>Federal Trade Commission</strong> <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/consumer-alerts/2023/10/you-now-have-permanent-access-free-weekly-credit-reports" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the bureaus had permanently extended a program that lets you check your credit report once a week for free.</p>
<p>If you haven’t done this in a while, now would be an excellent time to order your files. To place a freeze, you&#8217;ll need to create an account at each of the three major reporting bureaus, <a href="https://www.equifax.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equifax</a>, <a href="https://www.experian.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Experian</a> and <a href="https://www.transunion.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TransUnion</a>. Once you’ve established an account, you should be able to then view and freeze your credit file. If you spot errors, such as random addresses and phone numbers you don’t recognize, do not ignore them. Dispute any inaccuracies you may find.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/national-public-data-published-its-own-passwords/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>127</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NationalPublicData.com Hack Exposes a Nation&#8217;s Data</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-com-hack-exposes-a-nations-data/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-com-hack-exposes-a-nations-data/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 22:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlas Data Privacy Corp.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HaveIBeenPwned.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[InfraGard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Checkmate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerico Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Criminal Data LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Public Data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PeopleConnect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recordscheck.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sal Verini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salvatore Verini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shadowglade LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SXUL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trinity Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Troy Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TruthFinder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twisted History LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDoD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VX-Underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A great many readers this month reported receiving alerts that their Social Security Number, name, address and other personal information were exposed in a breach at a little-known but aptly-named consumer data broker called NationalPublicData.com. This post examines what we know about a breach that has exposed hundreds of millions of consumer records. We'll also take a closer look at the data broker that got hacked -- a background check company founded by an actor and retired sheriff's deputy from Florida.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A great many readers this month reported receiving alerts that their Social Security Number, name, address and other personal information were exposed in a breach at a little-known but aptly-named consumer data broker called <strong>NationalPublicData.com</strong>. This post examines what we know about a breach that has exposed hundreds of millions of consumer records. We&#8217;ll also take a closer look at the data broker that got hacked &#8212; a background check company founded by an actor and retired sheriff&#8217;s deputy from Florida.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-68389" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-home.png" alt="" width="1269" height="745" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-home.png 1269w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-home-768x451.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-home-782x459.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 1269px) 100vw, 1269px" /></p>
<p>On July 21, 2024, denizens of the cybercrime community <strong>Breachforums</strong> released more than 4 terabytes of data they claimed was stolen from nationalpublicdata.com, a Florida-based company that collects data on consumers and processes background checks.</p>
<p>The breach tracking service <strong>HaveIBeenPwned.com</strong> and the cybercrime-focused Twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vx-underground</a> both concluded the leak is the same information first put up for sale in April 2024 by a prolific cybercriminal who goes by the name &#8220;<strong>USDoD</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>On April 7, USDoD posted a sales thread on Breachforums for four terabytes of data &#8212; 2.9 billion rows of records &#8212; they claimed was taken from nationalpublicdata.com. The snippets of stolen data that USDoD offered as teasers showed rows of names, addresses, phone numbers, and Social Security Numbers (SSNs). Their asking price? $3.5 million.</p>
<p>Many media outlets mistakenly reported that the National Public data breach affects 2.9 billion people (that figure actually refers to the number of rows in the leaked data sets). HaveIBeenPwned.com&#8217;s <strong>Troy Hunt</strong> <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/inside-the-3-billion-people-national-public-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">analyzed the leaked data</a> and found it is a somewhat disparate collection of consumer and business records, including the real names, addresses, phone numbers and SSNs of millions of Americans (both living and deceased), and 70 million rows from a database of U.S. criminal records.</p>
<p>Hunt said he found 137 million unique email addresses in the leaked data, but stressed that there were no email addresses in the files containing SSN records.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you find yourself in this data breach via HaveIBeenPwned.com, there&#8217;s no evidence your SSN was leaked, and if you&#8217;re in the same boat as me, the data next to your record may not even be correct.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nationalpublicdata.com publicly acknowledged a breach in <a href="https://nationalpublicdata.com/Breach.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement on Aug. 12</a>, saying &#8220;there appears to have been a data security incident that may have involved some of your personal information. The incident appears to have involved a third-party bad actor that was trying to hack into data in late December 2023, with potential leaks of certain data in April 2024 and summer 2024.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company said the information &#8220;suspected of being breached&#8221; contained name, email address, phone number, social security number, and mailing address(es).</p>
<p>&#8220;We cooperated with law enforcement and governmental investigators and conducted a review of the potentially affected records and will try to notify you if there are further significant developments applicable to you,&#8221; the statement continues. &#8220;We have also implemented additional security measures in efforts to prevent the reoccurrence of such a breach and to protect our systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hunt&#8217;s analysis didn&#8217;t say how many unique SSNs were included in the leaked data. But according to researchers at <strong>Atlas Data Privacy Corp.</strong>, there are 272 million unique SSNs in the entire records set.</p>
<p>Atlas found most records have a name, SSN, and home address, and that approximately 26 percent of those records included a phone number. Atlas said they verified 5,000 addresses and phone numbers, and found the records pertain to people born before Jan. 1, 2002 (with very few exceptions).</p>
<p>If there is a tiny silver lining to the breach it is this: Atlas discovered that many of the records related to people who are now almost certainly deceased. They found the average age of the consumer in these records is 70, and fully two million records are related to people whose date of birth would make them more than 120 years old today.<span id="more-68375"></span></p>
<h2>TWISTED HISTORY</h2>
<p>Where did National Public Data get its consumer data? The company&#8217;s website doesn&#8217;t say, but it is operated by an entity in Coral Springs, Fla. called <strong>Jerico Pictures Inc.</strong> The website for Jerico Pictures is not currently responding. However, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230330052412/http://www.jericopictures.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cached versions of it at archive.org</a> show it is a film studio with offices in Los Angeles and South Florida.</p>
<p>The Florida Secretary of State says Jerico Pictures is owned by <strong>Salvatore (Sal) Verini Jr.</strong>, a retired deputy with the Broward County Sheriff&#8217;s office. The Secretary of State also says Mr. Verini is or was a founder of several other Florida companies, including <strong>National Criminal Data LLC</strong>, <strong>Twisted History LLC</strong>, <strong>Shadowglade LLC</strong> and <strong>Trinity Entertainment Inc.</strong>, among others.</p>
<p>Mr. Verini did not respond to multiple requests for comment. Cached copies of Mr. Verini&#8217;s vanity domain <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230323175843/http://www.salvatoreverini.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">salvatoreverini.com</a> recount his experience in acting (e.g. a role in a 1980s detective drama with Burt Reynolds) and more recently producing dramas and documentaries for several streaming channels.</p>
<div id="attachment_68384" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68384" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68384" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/salverini-imdb.png" alt="" width="749" height="546" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/salverini-imdb.png 849w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/salverini-imdb-768x560.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/salverini-imdb-782x570.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68384" class="wp-caption-text">Sal Verini&#8217;s profile page at imdb.com.</p></div>
<p>Pivoting on the email address used to register that vanity domain, <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> finds several other domains whose history offers a clearer picture of the types of data sources relied upon by National Public Data.</p>
<p>One of those domains is <strong>recordscheck.net</strong> (formerly <strong>recordscheck.info</strong>), which advertises &#8220;instant background checks, SSN traces, employees screening and more.&#8221; Another now-defunct business tied to Mr. Verini&#8217;s email &#8212; <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150110212648/http://www.publicrecordsunlimited.com/products.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">publicrecordsunlimited.com</a> &#8212; said it obtained consumer data from a variety of sources, including: birth, marriage and death records; voting records; professional licenses; state and federal criminal records.</p>
<div id="attachment_68387" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68387" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68387" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/publicrecordsunlimited.png" alt="" width="750" height="687" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/publicrecordsunlimited.png 870w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/publicrecordsunlimited-768x704.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/publicrecordsunlimited-782x716.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68387" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage for publicrecordsunlimited.com, per archive.org circa 2017.</p></div>
<p>It remains unclear how thieves originally obtained these records from National Public Data. KrebsOnSecurity sought comment from USDoD, who is perhaps best known for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/12/fbis-vetted-info-sharing-network-infragard-hacked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hacking into Infragard, an FBI program</a> that facilitates information sharing about cyber and physical threats with vetted people in the private sector.</p>
<p>USDoD said they indeed sold the same data set that was leaked on Breachforums this past month, but that the person who leaked the data did not obtain it from them. USDoD said the data stolen from National Public Data had traded hands several times since it was initially stolen in December 2023.</p>
<p>&#8220;The database has been floating around for a while,&#8221; USDoD said. &#8220;I was not the first one to get it.&#8221;</p>
<p>USDoD said the person who originally stole the data from NPD was a hacker who goes by the handle <strong>SXUL</strong>. That user appears to have deleted their Telegram account several days ago, presumably in response to intense media coverage of the breach.</p>
<h2>ANALYSIS</h2>
<p>Data brokers like National Public Data typically get their information by scouring federal, state and local government records. Those government files include voting registries, property filings, marriage certificates, motor vehicle records, criminal records, court documents, death records, professional licenses, bankruptcy filings, and more.</p>
<p>Americans may believe they have the right to opt out of having these records collected and sold to anyone. But experts say these underlying sources of information &#8212; the above-mentioned &#8220;public&#8221; records &#8212; are carved out from every single state consumer privacy law. This includes California&#8217;s privacy regime, which is often held up as the national leader in state privacy regulations.</p>
<p>You see, here in America, virtually anyone can become a consumer data broker. And with few exceptions, there aren&#8217;t any special requirements for brokers to show that they actually care about protecting the data they collect, store, repackage and sell so freely.</p>
<p>In February 2023, <strong>PeopleConnect</strong>, the owners of the background search services <strong>TruthFinder</strong> and <strong>Instant Checkmate</strong>, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/truthfinder-instant-checkmate-confirm-data-breach-affecting-20m-customers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acknowledged a breach affecting 20 million customers</a> who paid the data brokers to run background checks. The data exposed included email addresses, hashed passwords, first and last names, and phone numbers.</p>
<p>In 2019, malicious hackers <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/billion-records-exposed-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stole data on more than 1.5 billion people from People Data Labs</a>, a San Francisco data broker whose people-search services linked hundreds of millions of email addresses, LinkedIn and Facebook profiles and more than 200 million valid cell phone numbers.</p>
<p>These data brokers are the digital equivalent of massive oil tankers wandering the coast without GPS or an anchor, because when they get hacked, the effect is very much akin to the ecological and economic fallout from a giant oil spill.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an apt analogy because the dissemination of so much personal data all at once has ripple effects for months and years to come, as this information invariably feeds into a vast underground ocean of scammers who are already equipped and staffed to commit identity theft and account takeovers at scale.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also apt because much like with real-life oil spills, the cleanup costs and effort from data spills &#8212; even just vast collections of technically &#8220;public&#8221; documents like the NPD corpus &#8212; can be enormous, and most of the costs associated with that fall to consumers, directly or indirectly.</p>
<h2>WHAT SHOULD YOU DO?</h2>
<p>Should you worry that your SSN and other personal data might be exposed in this breach? That isn&#8217;t necessary for people who&#8217;ve been following the advice here for years, which is to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/09/credit-freezes-are-free-let-the-ice-age-begin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">freeze one&#8217;s credit file</a> at <a href="https://www.usa.gov/credit-freeze" target="_blank" rel="noopener">each of the major consumer reporting bureaus</a>. Having a freeze on your files makes it much harder for identity thieves to create new accounts in your name, and it limits who can view your credit information.</p>
<p>The main reason I recommend the freeze is that all of the information ID thieves need to assume your identity is now broadly available from multiple sources, thanks to the multiplicity of data breaches we&#8217;ve seen involving SSN data and other key static data points about people.</p>
<p>But beyond that, there are numerous cybercriminal services that offer detailed background checks on consumers, including full SSNs. These services are powered by compromised accounts at data brokers that cater to private investigators and law enforcement officials, and some are now fully automated via Telegram instant message bots. Meaning, if you&#8217;re an American who hasn&#8217;t frozen their credit files and you haven&#8217;t yet experienced some form of new account fraud, the ID thieves probably just haven&#8217;t gotten around to you yet.</p>
<p>All Americans are also entitled to obtain a free copy of their credit report weekly from each of the three major credit bureaus. It used to be that consumers were allowed one free report from each of the bureaus annually, but in October 2023 the <strong>Federal Trade Commission</strong> <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/consumer-alerts/2023/10/you-now-have-permanent-access-free-weekly-credit-reports" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the bureaus had permanently extended a program that lets you check your credit report once a week for free.</p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t done this in a while, now would be an excellent time to order your files. To place a freeze, you need to create an account at each of the three major reporting bureaus, <a href="https://www.equifax.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equifax</a>, <a href="https://www.experian.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Experian</a> and <a href="https://www.transunion.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TransUnion</a>. Once you&#8217;ve established an account, you should be able to then view and freeze your credit file. Dispute any inaccuracies you may find. If you spot errors, such as random addresses and phone numbers you don&#8217;t recognize, do not ignore them: Identity theft and new account fraud are not problems that get easier to solve by letting them fester.</p>
<p>Mr. Verini probably didn&#8217;t respond to requests for comment because his company is <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/background-check-data-of-3-billion-stolen-in-breach-suit-says?ref=troyhunt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">now the subject of a class-action lawsuit</a> (NB: the lawsuit also erroneously claims 3 billion people were affected). These lawsuits are practically inevitable now after a major breach, but they also have the unfortunate tendency to let regulators and lawmakers off the hook.</p>
<p>Almost every time there&#8217;s a major breach of SSN data, Americans are offered credit monitoring services. Most of the time, those services come from one of the three major consumer credit bureaus, the same companies that profit by compiling and selling incredibly detailed dossiers on consumers&#8217; financial lives. The same companies that use dark patterns to trick people into paying for &#8220;credit lock&#8221; services that achieve a similar result as a freeze but still let the bureaus sell your data to their partners.</p>
<p>But class-actions alone will not drive us toward a national conversation about what needs to change. Americans currently have very few rights to opt out of the personal and financial surveillance, data collection and sale that is pervasive in today&#8217;s tech-based economy.</p>
<p>The breach at National Public Data may not be the worst data breach ever. But it does present yet another opportunity for this country&#8217;s leaders to acknowledge that the SSN has completely failed as a measure of authentication or authorization. It was never a good idea to use as an authenticator to begin with, and it is certainly no longer suitable for this purpose.</p>
<p>The truth is that these data brokers will continue to proliferate and thrive (and get hacked and relieved of their data) until Congress begins to realize it’s time for some consumer privacy and data protection laws that are relevant to life in the 21st century.</p>
<p>Further reporting: <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/national-public-data-published-its-own-passwords/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">National Public Data Published Its Own Passwords</a></p>
<p><strong>Update, Aug. 16, 8:00 a.m. ET:</strong> Corrected the story to note that consumers can now obtain a free credit report from each of the three consumer reporting bureaus weekly, instead of just annually.</p>
<p><strong>Update, Aug. 23, 12:33 p.m. ET:</strong> Added link to latest story on NPD breach.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/nationalpublicdata-com-hack-exposes-a-nations-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six 0-Days Lead Microsoft&#8217;s August 2024 Patch Push</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/six-0-days-lead-microsofts-august-2024-patch-push/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/six-0-days-lead-microsofts-august-2024-patch-push/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 21:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38106]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38107]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38178]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38189]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38193]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38213]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kev Breen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark of the web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Edge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zero Day Initiative]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=68355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to fix at least 90 security vulnerabilities in Windows and related software, including a whopping six zero-day flaws that are already being actively exploited by attackers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to fix at least 90 security vulnerabilities in <strong>Windows</strong> and related software, including <em>a whopping six zero-day flaws</em> that are already being actively exploited by attackers.</p>
<div id="attachment_68358" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68358" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68358" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/clicktofix.png" alt="" width="750" height="516" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/clicktofix.png 757w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/clicktofix-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68358" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock.</p></div>
<p>This month&#8217;s bundle of update joy from Redmond includes patches for security holes in <strong>Office</strong>, <strong>.NET</strong>, <strong>Visual Studio</strong>, <strong>Azure</strong>, <strong>Co-Pilot</strong>, <strong>Microsoft Dynamics</strong>, <strong>Teams</strong>, <strong>Secure Boot,</strong> and of course Windows itself. Of the six zero-day weaknesses Microsoft addressed this month, half are local privilege escalation vulnerabilities &#8212; meaning they are primarily useful for attackers when combined with other flaws or access.</p>
<p><a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38106" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38106</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38107" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38107</a> and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38193" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38193</a> all allow an attacker to gain SYSTEM level privileges on a vulnerable machine, although the vulnerabilities reside in different parts of the Windows operating system.</p>
<p>Microsoft&#8217;s advisories include little information about the last two privilege escalation flaws, other than to note they are being actively exploited. Microsoft says CVE-2024-38106 exists in the Windows Kernel and is being actively exploited, but that it has a high &#8220;attack complexity,&#8221; meaning it can be tricky for malware or miscreants to exploit reliably.</p>
<p>&#8220;Microsoft lists exploit complexity as high due to the attacker needing to win a race condition,&#8221; Trend Micro&#8217;s <strong>ZeroDay Initiative</strong> (ZDI) noted. &#8220;However, some races are easier to run than others. It’s times like this where the CVSS can be misleading. Race conditions do lead to complexity high in the CVSS score, but with attacks in the wild, it’s clear this bug is readily exploitable.&#8221;<span id="more-68355"></span></p>
<p>Another zero-day this month is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38178" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38178</a>, a remote code execution flaw that exists when the built-in <strong>Windows Edge</strong> browser is operating in &#8220;Internet Explorer Mode.&#8221; IE mode is not on by default in Edge, but it can be enabled to work with older websites or applications that aren&#8217;t supported by modern Chromium-based browsers.</p>
<p>&#8220;While this is not the default mode for most users, this exploit being actively exploited suggests that there are occasions in which the attacker can set this or has identified an organization (or user) that has this configuration,&#8221; wrote <strong>Kev Breen</strong>, senior director of threat research at Immersive Labs.</p>
<p><a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38213" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38213</a> is a zero-day flaw that allows malware to bypass the &#8220;Mark of the Web,&#8221; a security feature in Windows that marks files downloaded from the Internet as untrusted (this Windows Smartscreen feature is responsible for the &#8220;Windows protected your PC&#8221; popup that appears when opening files downloaded from the Web).</p>
<p>&#8220;This vulnerability is not exploitable on its own and is typically seen as part of an exploit chain, for example, modifying a malicious document or exe file to include this bypass before sending the file via email or distributing on compromised websites,&#8221; Breen said.</p>
<p>The final zero-day this month is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-38189" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-38189</a>, a remote code execution flaw in <strong>Microsoft Project</strong>. However, Microsoft and multiple security firms point out that this vulnerability only works on customers who have already disabled notifications about the security risks of running VBA Macros in Microsoft Project (not the best idea, as malware has a long history of hiding within malicious Office Macros).</p>
<p>Separately, <strong>Adobe</strong> today released 11 security bulletins addressing at least 71 security vulnerabilities across a range of products, including <strong>Adobe Illustrator</strong>, <strong>Dimension</strong>, <strong>Photoshop</strong>, <strong>InDesign</strong>, <strong>Acrobat</strong> and <strong>Reader</strong>, <strong>Bridge</strong>, <strong>Substance 3D Stager</strong>, <strong>Commerce</strong>, <strong>InCopy</strong>, and <strong>Substance 3D Sampler/Substance 3D Designer</strong>. Adobe says it is not aware of active exploitation against any of the flaws it fixed this week.</p>
<p>It’s a good idea for Windows users to stay current with security updates from Microsoft, which can quickly pile up otherwise. That doesn’t mean you have to install them on Patch Tuesday each month. Indeed, waiting a day or three before updating is a sane response, given that sometimes updates go awry and usually within a few days Microsoft has fixed any issues with its patches. It’s also smart to back up your data and/or image your Windows drive before applying new updates.</p>
<p>For a more detailed breakdown of the individual flaws addressed by Microsoft today, check out the <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft%20August%202024%20Patch%20Tuesday/31164/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center’s list</a>. For those admins responsible for maintaining larger Windows environments, it pays to keep an eye on <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Askwoody.com</a>, which frequently points out when specific Microsoft updates are creating problems for a number of users.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/six-0-days-lead-microsofts-august-2024-patch-push/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 281/281 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2024-09-17 13:06:42 by W3 Total Cache
-->
