<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
                    <title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/</link>
            <language>en-us</language> 
            <description>Phys.org internet news portal provides the latest news on science including: Physics, Nanotechnology, Life Sciences, Space Science, Earth Science, Environment, Health and Medicine.</description>
                        <item>
                <title>New method improves understanding of light-wave propagation in anisotropic materials</title>
                <description>Understanding how light travels through various materials is essential for many fields, from medical imaging to manufacturing. However, due to their structure, materials often show directional differences in how they scatter light, known as anisotropy. This complexity has traditionally made it difficult to accurately measure and model their optical properties. Recently, researchers have developed a new technique that could transform how we study these materials.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-method-propagation-anisotropic-materials.html</link>
                <category>Optics &amp; Photonics </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:09:55 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645797385</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/new-method-improves-un.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Team discovers naturally occurring DNA-protein hybrids</title>
                <description>Thanks to a serendipitous discovery and a lot of painstaking work, scientists can now build biohybrid molecules that combine the homing powers of DNA with the broad functional repertoire of proteins—without having to synthesize them one by one, researchers report in a new study. Using a naturally occurring process, laboratories can harness the existing molecule-building capacities of bacteria to generate vast libraries of potentially therapeutic DNA-protein hybrid molecules.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-team-naturally-dna-protein-hybrids.html</link>
                <category>Biochemistry </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:07:03 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645797221</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/team-discovers-natural.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Black hole pairs may unveil new particles</title>
                <description>In a paper published in Physical Review Letters this week, physicists from Amsterdam and Copenhagen argue that close observations of merging black hole pairs may unveil information about potential new particles. The research combines several new discoveries made by UvA scientists over the past six years.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-black-hole-pairs-unveil-particles.html</link>
                <category>General Physics </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:05:03 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645797102</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/black-hole-pairs-may-u-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>An unexpected protein connection in maize growth and defense could enhance crop resilience</title>
                <description>Maize (corn) is one of the most important staple crops in the world and has been extensively studied. Yet, many aspects of the genetic mechanisms regulating its growth and development remain unexplored.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-unexpected-protein-maize-growth-defense.html</link>
                <category>Molecular &amp; Computational biology Agriculture </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:58:48 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645796725</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2020/maize.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Portugal battles ferocious wildfires as toll rises to seven</title>
                <description>Thousands of firefighters on Tuesday battled wildfires in Portugal that have killed seven people and burnt more land in a matter of days than the rest of the summer combined.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-portugal-ferocious-wildfires-toll.html</link>
                <category>Environment </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:50:02 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795269</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/portugal-is-battling-t.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Hubble finds more black holes than expected in the early universe</title>
                <description>With the help of NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, an international team of researchers led by scientists in the Department of Astronomy at Stockholm University has found more black holes in the early universe than has previously been reported. The new result can help scientists understand how supermassive black holes were created.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-hubble-black-holes-early-universe.html</link>
                <category>Astronomy </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:49:56 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645796190</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/nasas-hubble-finds-mor-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Scientists from 33 European countries join forces to generate reference genomes for the continent's biological diversity</title>
                <description>In a new publication, the European Reference Genome Atlas (ERGA) announces the success of its pilot project. This initiative assembled a large collaborative network of scientists and institutions across 33 countries to produce high-quality reference genomes of 98 European species—so far. The pilot project has provided valuable lessons and highlighted key challenges, positioning ERGA as a model for decentralized, inclusive and equitable biodiversity genomics initiatives around the world.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-scientists-european-countries-generate-genomes.html</link>
                <category>Plants &amp; Animals Molecular &amp; Computational biology </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:49:43 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645796178</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/scientists-from-33-eur.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>People underestimate the income of the top 1%, researchers find</title>
                <description>People selectively underestimate how rich the world's richest people are, according to a study. Increasing income inequality in many countries is driven by steep gains among the top 1% of earners. In the United States, support for policies that would redistribute wealth has not increased since the 1970s, even as the share of incomes held by the top 1% of Americans jumped from 10% to 19%.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-people-underestimate-income.html</link>
                <category>Economics &amp; Business Political science </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:44:50 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795886</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/wealthy.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>National political dialogue focuses on power and morals, finds study</title>
                <description>A study of political speeches, social media posts from politicians, and Reddit discussions among everyday users finds a higher prevalence of abstract, moralized, and power-centric language in national versus local politics. Political dialogue and debate in the United States has largely shifted from the local to the national in recent years, in part due to the decline of local news media. However, national discussions lack the concrete common ground that comes from shared place-based knowledge.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-national-political-dialogue-focuses-power.html</link>
                <category>Political science </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:41:02 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795661</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/national-political-dia.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Storm Boris toll rises to 21 in central Europe</title>
                <description>The death toll has risen to 21 in the extreme weather and flooding let loose by Storm Boris in central Europe, authorities said Tuesday after two more victims were reported in Poland and one in Austria.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-storm-boris-toll-central-europe.html</link>
                <category>Environment </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:40:01 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795177</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/an-81-year-old-woman-w.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Synthetic mini-motor: Researchers convert chemical energy into rotational energy at the supramolecular level</title>
                <description>Researchers at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) have developed an artificial motor at the supramolecular level that can develop impressive power. This wind-up motor is a tiny ribbon made of special molecules. When energy is applied, this ribbon aligns itself, moves like a small fin and can thus push objects. For the first time, the energy for this comes from a chemical fuel.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-synthetic-mini-motor-chemical-energy.html</link>
                <category>Materials Science </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:40:01 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795309</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/synthetic-mini-motor-r.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Leveraging body-camera footage to analyze police training impact</title>
                <description>A study used body-worn camera footage as a source of data on police-community interactions. Nicholas Camp and colleagues analyzed transcripts from 615 police stops made in California by Oakland Police Department police officers before and after a procedural justice training, which focused on officer communication in routine traffic stops. The training included findings by the authors in a previous study that showed officers used more respectful language with White drivers than with Black drivers during traffic stops.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-leveraging-body-camera-footage-police.html</link>
                <category>Political science </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:35:05 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795301</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2022/police-body-camera.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Study sheds light on trade-off between noise and power in nanoscale heat engines</title>
                <description>Thanks to nanoscale devices as small as human cells, researchers can create groundbreaking material properties, leading to smaller, faster, and more energy-efficient electronics. However, to fully unlock the potential of nanotechnology, addressing noise is crucial.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-noise-power-nanoscale.html</link>
                <category>Nanophysics Nanomaterials </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:34:04 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645795241</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/new-understanding-of-t.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Thousands of students in Scotland at risk of homelessness</title>
                <description>Thousands of students across Scotland are at risk of homelessness and unable to access the right housing in the country's biggest cities, according to a new report co-authored by researchers from the University of Glasgow.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-thousands-students-scotland-homelessness.html</link>
                <category>Economics &amp; Business Education </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794679</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/edinburgh-scotland-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>The power of one: Study finds solitary carnivores outkill group hunters</title>
                <description>Earth's majestic &quot;apex predators&quot; are some of the most prolific hunters in the world. But which ones kill the most?</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-power-solitary-carnivores-outkill-group.html</link>
                <category>Plants &amp; Animals Ecology </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794437</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/cougar.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>New study links US decline in volunteering to economic conditions</title>
                <description>Volunteering used to be a mainstay of U.S. culture. But in recent years, giving back to their community hasn't played as big a role in many Americans' lives.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-links-decline-volunteering-economic-conditions.html</link>
                <category>Social Sciences Economics &amp; Business </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:25:15 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794707</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/volunteer-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Analysis finds mobile phone distractions adversely affect learning in young adults</title>
                <description>A new analysis by University at Albany researchers in the School of Education has found that young adults exposed to mobile technology distractions had worse learning outcomes in the classroom compared to those without distractions.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-analysis-mobile-distractions-adversely-affect.html</link>
                <category>Social Sciences Education </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:21:57 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794512</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/smartphone.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>New data reveals rates of family violence among those who died by suicide</title>
                <description>Domestic, family and sexual violence is rightly recognized as a national crisis.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-reveals-family-violence-died-suicide.html</link>
                <category>Social Sciences </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:21:23 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794477</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/stress-4.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Archaeological excavation in ancient Fregellae reveals the end of a cultural landscape</title>
                <description>From 22 July to 19 August 2024, a team of researchers from the Leibniz-Zentrum für Archäologie (LEIZA) and the University of Trier investigated the remains of the late Republican city of Fregellae in present-day Italy to better understand the social and economic fabric of the region before and after its destruction in 125 BCE.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-archaeological-excavation-ancient-fregellae-reveals.html</link>
                <category>Archaeology </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:20:26 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794419</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/archaeological-excavat.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Scientists decipher the energy patterns in our cells</title>
                <description>Our cells harness energy for essential functions such as division, wound healing, and our immune response to diseases including cancer. But until now, the mechanics of how that energy affects cell behavior—and how this relates to health outcomes—have remained elusive.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-scientists-decipher-energy-patterns-cells.html</link>
                <category>Cell &amp; Microbiology Molecular &amp; Computational biology </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:20:18 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794405</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/scientists-decipher-th.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Urban sustainable development needs to secure basic human needs, finds study</title>
                <description>Urban sustainable development (USD) plans and policies cover a wide range of issues, such as biodiversity protection, transportation, or poverty reduction. Yet, it is unclear what the USD policy preferences of residents are.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-urban-sustainable-basic-human.html</link>
                <category>Environment </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:20:06 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794400</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/urban-sustainable-deve.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Antarctic krill can lock away similar levels of carbon as seagrass and mangroves, finds study</title>
                <description>Small marine crustaceans are as valuable as key coastal habitats for storing carbon and should be similarly protected, according to new research.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-antarctic-krill-similar-carbon-seagrass.html</link>
                <category>Ecology </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:19:04 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645794341</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/antarctic-krill-can-lo-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Fungi to the rescue: South African scientists use innovative approach to protect apple trees</title>
                <description>Gardeners the world over dread the appearance of aphids on their plants. There are around 4,000 species of these sap-sucking insects and about 250 are pests that can wreak havoc on crops in a garden or orchard.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-fungi-south-african-scientists-approach.html</link>
                <category>Ecology Agriculture </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:13:03 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793981</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/apples.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Saved from extinction? New modeling suggests a hopeful future for te reo Māori language</title>
                <description>Just four years ago, experts warned te reo Māori was on a &quot;pathway towards extinction&quot; unless resources were put into teaching young Māori.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-extinction-future-te-reo-mori.html</link>
                <category>Social Sciences </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:11:06 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793862</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2022/language.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Are kiwi and moa recent immigrants from Australia? Neither fossils nor genetic evidence support the story</title>
                <description>Aotearoa New Zealand is a land of birds, from the smallest of wrens to the mightiest of moa. The ancestors of some species have been here for tens of millions of years, while others arrived only a few million years ago.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-kiwi-moa-immigrants-australia-fossils.html</link>
                <category>Molecular &amp; Computational biology Paleontology &amp; Fossils </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:01:04 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793262</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/are-kiwi-and-moa-recen-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>UK public is becoming more 'carbon capable'—here's what that means</title>
                <description>As climate change intensifies, rising public awareness and incremental behavioral changes will hopefully evolve into transformative action. We investigate how lifestyles and systems of governance need to change to bring about a sustainable, low-carbon future in the UK.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-uk-carbon-capable.html</link>
                <category>Environment </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:00:17 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793205</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/uk-public-is-becoming.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>The Trump–Harris debate shows how personality can reveal itself in language</title>
                <description>An analysis of the choice of words by American presidential candidates Kamala Harris and Donald Trump in their recent debate reveals five insights into their personalities.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-trumpharris-debate-personality-reveal-language.html</link>
                <category>Social Sciences Political science </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:00:14 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793201</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/the-trump-harris-debat.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Central America could play troubling new role in cocaine trade: Study finds some countries agriculturally 'ideal'</title>
                <description>For many decades, the coca plant—the main ingredient in cocaine—has been grown almost exclusively in South America. But a new study shows that nearly half of northern Central America appears to be highly suitable for cultivating this lucrative cash crop.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-central-america-play-role-cocaine.html</link>
                <category>Environment </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645782267</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/central-america-could.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Astronomers are getting better at detecting asteroids before they hit Earth—and it could save us from catastrophe</title>
                <description>On September 4 2024, astronomers discovered an asteroid, 1 meter in diameter, heading towards Earth. The space rock would burn up harmlessly in the atmosphere near the Philippines later that day, officials announced. Nevertheless, it produced a spectacular fireball that was shared in videos posted on social media.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-astronomers-asteroids-earth-catastrophe.html</link>
                <category>Astronomy Planetary Sciences </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:59:04 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793141</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/astronomers-are-gettin.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                        <item>
                <title>Advertising a house is ridiculously expensive in Australia—could that be affecting the property market?</title>
                <description>Australia has long been one of the most expensive places in the world to buy a house. Now, it's apparently also one of the costliest places to sell one.</description>
                <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-09-advertising-house-ridiculously-expensive-australia.html</link>
                <category>Economics &amp; Business </category>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 11:58:04 EDT</pubDate>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">news645793082</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/picture-of-house.jpg" width="90" height="90" />            </item>
                    </channel>
</rss>

