<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MIT Technology Review</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.technologyreview.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.technologyreview.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:30:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/cropped-TR-Logo-Block-Centered-R.png?w=32</url>
	<title>MIT Technology Review</title>
	<link>https://www.technologyreview.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">172986898</site>	<item>
		<title>The Download: OpenAI&#8217;s latest model, and 4D printing&#8217;s potential</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/17/1104008/the-download-openais-latest-model-and-4d-printings-potential/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Download]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1104008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Why OpenAI’s new model is such a big deal Last week OpenAI released a new model called o1 (previously referred to under the code name “Strawberry” and, before that, Q*) that blows GPT-4o&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Why OpenAI’s new model is such a big deal</strong></p>



<p>Last week OpenAI released a new model called o1 (previously referred to under the code name “Strawberry” and, before that, Q*) that blows GPT-4o out of the water.<br><br>Unlike previous models that are well suited for language tasks like writing and editing, OpenAI o1 is focused on multistep “reasoning,” the type of process required for advanced mathematics, coding, or other STEM-based questions. The model is also trained to answer PhD-level questions in subjects ranging from astrophysics to organic chemistry.<br><br>The bulk of LLM progress until now has been language-driven, but in addition to getting lots of facts wrong, such LLMs have failed to demonstrate the types of skills required to solve important problems in fields like drug discovery, materials science, coding, or physics. OpenAI’s o1 is one of the first signs that LLMs might soon become genuinely helpful companions to human researchers in these fields. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/17/1104004/why-openais-new-model-is-such-a-big-deal/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—James O’Donnell</em></p>



<p><strong>This story is from The Algorithm, our weekly newsletter giving you the inside track on all things AI. </strong><a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/ai-demystified-the-algorithm/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>Sign up</strong></a><strong> to receive it in your inbox every Monday.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>This designer creates magic from everyday materials</strong></p>



<p>Back in 2012, designer and computer scientist Skylar Tibbits started working on 3D-printed materials that could change their shape or properties after being printed—a concept that Tibbits dubbed “4D printing,” where the fourth dimension is time.<br><br>Today, 4D printing is its own field—the subject of a professional society and thousands of papers, with researchers around the world looking into potential applications from self-adjusting biomedical devices to soft robotics.<br><br>But not long after 4D printing took off, Tibbits was already looking toward a new challenge: What other capabilities can we build into materials? And can we do that <em>without printing</em>? <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/27/1096638/skylar-tibbits-4-d-printing-materials-transformation/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Anna Gibbs</em></p>



<p><strong>This piece is from the </strong><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/magazines/the-next-125-years-issue/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>latest print issue</strong></a><strong> of MIT Technology Review, which celebrates 125 years of the magazine! If you don’t already, </strong><a href="https://ter.li/125th-Live-Download"><strong>subscribe now to get 25% off </strong></a><strong>future copies once they land.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>A special preview of EmTech MIT: AI, Climate, and the new rules of business</strong></p>



<p>Artificial intelligence and climate technologies are the two greatest forces impacting business decisions today. This year at EmTech MIT, our annual flagship conference, we examine the breakthroughs, concerns, and the near-future possibilities brought on by AI, as well as the climate technologies building the green economy.</p>



<p><strong>Register </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/events/7232398166988390401/about/"><strong>here</strong></a><strong> to join us at 12.30pm ET today for a LinkedIn event previewing everything you can expect from this year’s event.</strong></p>



<p><strong>The must-reads</strong></p>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 TikTok had a rough day in court</strong></p>



<p>Federal judges questioned its argument that Congress lacks the authority to ban it. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/16/technology/tiktok-us-ban-case.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>If TikTok doesn’t break from its parent company, it’ll be banned on January 19 2025. </em>(<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b1c4c19f-094f-4e2c-a7c3-4285851e88fe">FT</a> $)<br>+ <em>There’s a good chance TikTok may have to escalate its fight to the Supreme Court. </em>(<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-16/tiktok-appeal-of-us-ban-over-china-ties-to-be-argued-in-court?sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+ <em>The depressing truth about TikTok’s impending ban. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/05/01/1091951/tiktok-ban-chinese-companies-political/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 Intel could receive up to $3 billion in chip grants</strong><br>To manufacture chips for the US military. (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-16/intel-confirms-3-billion-defense-department-chips-act-grant?srnd=phx-technology&amp;sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+ <em>Intel’s contract manufacturing business has inked a deal with Amazon. </em>(<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/intel-aws-expand-strategic-collaboration-chip-manufacturing-2024-09-16/">Reuters</a>)<br>+ <em>What’s next in chips. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/05/13/1092319/whats-next-in-chips/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)<br><br><strong>3 Apple’s new iOS 18 software is here<br></strong>But Apple Intelligence, its suite of AI tools, is nowhere to be seen. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/personal-tech/apple-ios18-update-features-iphone-961dd2e8?mod=tech_lead_pos4">WSJ</a> $)<br>+ <em>The new software is much more customizable than previous versions. </em>(<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/09/ios-18s-new-home-screen-features-are-a-long-awaited-win-for-flexibility/">Ars Technica</a>)<br>+ <em>Here are the best features worth paying attention to. </em>(<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/ios-18-best-new-features/">NYT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>4 Donald Trump has launched a new cryptocurrency business</strong><br>The venture looks an awful lot like a play to the crypto faithful. (<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/16/politics/trump-cryptocurrency-business/index.html">CNN</a>)<br>+ <em>Trump doesn’t seem to know a great deal about crypto. </em>(<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-offers-little-detail-crypto-business-unveiling-2024-09-17/">Reuters</a>)<br>+ <em>Opportunists are already taking advantage of Trump’s fans. </em>(<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/16/24246805/trump-world-liberty-financial-crypto-platform-announcement">The Verge</a>)</p>



<p><strong>5 More Meta smartglasses are likely to be on their way</strong><br>The company signed a 10-year extension deal with glasses maker EssilorLuxottica. (<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/essilorluxottica-expands-smart-glasses-partnership-with-meta-2024-09-17/">Reuters</a>)</p>



<p><strong>6 Working in a data center is like firefighting<br></strong>Human workers are constantly on the lookout for technical issues. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/17/data-center-workers-jobs/">WP</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>7 Googling one of art’s most famous paintings returned AI slop</strong><br>Users searching for Hieronymus Bosch’s Garden of Earthly Delights were met with AI-generated garbage. (<a href="https://www.404media.co/google-serves-ai-slop-as-top-result-for-one-of-the-most-famous-paintings-in-history/">404 Media</a>)<br>+ <em>Why artists are becoming less scared of AI. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/06/18/1093998/why-artists-becoming-less-scared-of-ai/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>8 An Nvidia GPU purse can be yours for $1,024</strong><br>Hype? What hype? (<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/gpu-purses-nvidia-designer-2024-9">Insider</a> $)<br>+ <em>The company’s stranglehold on the chip industry is being closely watched. </em>(<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nvidia-ai">IEEE Spectrum</a>)</p>



<p><strong>9 Can you tell blue and green apart? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f535.png" alt="🔵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f7e2.png" alt="🟢" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><br>A new viral test plays with our personal color perception. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/wellness/2024/sep/16/blue-green-viral-test-color-perception">The Guardian</a>)  <br><br><strong>10 The latest YouTube trend? 80s weather reports</strong><br>Set to dreamy soundtracks. (<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/vaporwave-weatherwave-youtube-climate-change/">Wired</a> $)</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Quote of the day</strong></p>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>“The speech on TikTok is not Chinese speech. It is American speech.”</strong></p>



<p>—Jeffrey Fisher, a lawyer arguing on behalf of TikTok content creators, argues that banning the app in the US could violate the rights of Americans, the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c5y3y79llndo">BBC</a> reports.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The big story</strong></p>



<p><strong>Psychedelics are having a moment and women could be the ones to benefit</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/08/10/1057146/psychedelics-scentific-research-women/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*|SUBCLASS|*&amp;utm_content=*|DATE:m-d-Y|*"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd_EIVnL4OWyzsMEtcJiDdP5gbQMYm-BDf_2KFCCImq94Tx_7jpwGyBOJLrMM4AdU_vxyYN8JrooR_MoKn5tpXefCtkZs-uQBLhcVBTjJYC-Bd43pESgGLp5Y-ojSZwTOsrA54nC8PBYBu-MRltcMc74GU?key=JkWcM7R9Znw-tmWrkPRFqA" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/08/10/1057146/psychedelics-scentific-research-women/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"></a><strong>August 2022</strong></p>



<p>Psychedelics are having a moment. After decades of prohibition and vilification, they are increasingly being employed as therapeutics. Drugs like ketamine, MDMA, and psilocybin mushrooms are being studied in clinical trials to treat depression, substance abuse, and a range of other maladies.</p>



<p>And as these long-taboo drugs stage a comeback in the scientific community, it’s possible they could be especially promising for women. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/08/10/1057146/psychedelics-scentific-research-women/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Taylor Majewski</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></p>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction to brighten up your day. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/yannon_"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em></p>



<p>+ The artists who created these <a href="https://www.iamag.co/25-original-matte-painting-made-for-star-wars/">Star Wars matte paintings</a> for the films’ futuristic backdrops were supremely talented.<br>+ Madrid really loves <a href="https://www.vittlesmagazine.com/p/crisps-de-madrid">crisps</a> (or potato chips, to the uninitiated)<br>+ <a href="https://www.bustle.com/entertainment/organization-the-home-edit-restock-videos-tiktok-instagram">#Restock videos</a> are all the rage these days.<br>+ How to enjoy the great outdoors without getting <a href="https://www.outdoorlife.com/10-reasons-people-get-lost-in-wild/">lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1104008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why OpenAI’s new model is such a big deal</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/17/1104004/why-openais-new-model-is-such-a-big-deal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James O'Donnell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Algorithm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1104004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This story is from The Algorithm, our weekly newsletter on AI. To get it in your inbox first,&#160;sign up here. Last weekend, I got married at a summer camp, and during the day our guests competed in a series of games inspired by the show Survivor that my now-wife and I orchestrated. When we were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This story is from The Algorithm, our weekly newsletter on AI. To get it in your inbox first,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/ai-demystified-the-algorithm/"><em>sign up here</em></a><em>.</em></p>



<p>Last weekend, I got married at a summer camp, and during the day our guests competed in a series of games inspired by the show <em>Survivor</em> that my now-wife and I orchestrated. When we were planning the games in August, we wanted one station to be a memory challenge, where our friends and family would have to memorize part of a poem and then relay it to their teammates so they could re-create it with a set of wooden tiles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I thought OpenAI’s GPT-4o, its leading model at the time, would be perfectly suited to help. I asked it to create a short wedding-themed poem, with the constraint that each letter could only appear a certain number of times so we could make sure teams would be able to reproduce it with the provided set of tiles. GPT-4o failed miserably. The model repeatedly insisted that its poem worked within the constraints, even though it didn’t. It would correctly count the letters only after the fact, while continuing to deliver poems that didn’t fit the prompt. Without the time to meticulously craft the verses by hand, we ditched the poem idea and instead challenged guests to memorize a series of shapes made from colored tiles. (That ended up being a total hit with our friends and family, who also competed in dodgeball, egg tosses, and capture the flag.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, last week OpenAI <a href="https://openai.com/index/learning-to-reason-with-llms/">released</a> a new model called o1 (previously referred to under the code name “Strawberry” <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/11/27/1083886/unpacking-the-hype-around-openais-rumored-new-q-model/">and, before that, Q*</a>) that <strong>blows GPT-4o out of the water</strong> for this type of purpose<strong>.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Unlike previous models that are well suited for language tasks like writing and editing, OpenAI o1 is focused on multistep “reasoning,” the type of process required for advanced mathematics, coding, or other STEM-based questions. It uses a “chain of thought” technique, according to OpenAI. “It learns to recognize and correct its mistakes. It learns to break down tricky steps into simpler ones. It learns to try a different approach when the current one isn’t working,” the company wrote in a blog post on its website.</p>



<p><strong>OpenAI’s tests point to resounding success.</strong> The model ranks in the 89th percentile on questions from the competitive coding organization Codeforces and would be among the top 500 high school students in the USA Math Olympiad, which covers geometry, number theory, and other math topics. The model is also trained to answer PhD-level questions in subjects ranging from astrophysics to organic chemistry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In math olympiad questions, the new model is 83.3% accurate, versus 13.4% for GPT-4o. In the PhD-level <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2311.12022">questions</a>, it averaged 78% accuracy, compared with 69.7% from human experts and 56.1% from GPT-4o. (In light of these accomplishments, it’s unsurprising the new model was pretty good at writing a poem for our nuptial games, though still not perfect; it used more Ts and Ss than instructed to.)</p>



<p><strong>So why does this matter? </strong>The bulk of LLM progress until now has been language-driven, resulting in chatbots or voice assistants that can interpret, analyze, and generate words. But in addition to getting lots of facts wrong, such LLMs have failed to demonstrate the types of skills required to solve important problems in fields like drug discovery, materials science, coding, or physics. OpenAI’s o1 is one of the first signs that LLMs might soon become genuinely helpful companions to human researchers in these fields.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s a big deal because it brings “chain-of-thought” reasoning in an AI model to a mass audience, says Matt Welsh, an AI researcher and founder of the LLM startup Fixie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The reasoning abilities are directly in the model, rather than one having to use separate tools to achieve similar results. My expectation is that it will raise the bar for what people expect AI models to be able to do,” Welsh says.</p>



<p>That said, it’s best to take OpenAI’s comparisons to “human-level skills” with a grain of salt, says Yves-Alexandre de Montjoye, an associate professor in math and computer science at Imperial College London. It’s very hard to meaningfully compare how LLMs and people go about tasks such as solving math problems from scratch.</p>



<p>Also, AI researchers <a href="https://x.com/fchollet/status/1835452149851148727">say</a> that measuring how well a model like o1 can “reason” is harder than it sounds. If it answers a given question correctly, is that because it successfully reasoned its way to the logical answer? Or was it aided by a sufficient starting point of knowledge built into the model? The model “still falls short when it comes to open-ended reasoning,” Google AI researcher François Chollet <a href="https://x.com/fchollet/status/1835452149851148727">wrote</a> on X.</p>



<p>Finally, there’s the price. This reasoning-heavy model doesn’t come cheap. Though access to some versions of the model is included in premium OpenAI subscriptions, developers using o1 through the API will pay three times as much as they pay for GPT-4o—$15 per 1 million input tokens in o1, versus $5 for GPT-4o. The new model also won’t be most users’ first pick for more language-heavy tasks, where GPT-4o continues to be the better option, according to OpenAI’s user surveys.&nbsp;</p>





<p>What will it unlock? We won’t know until researchers and labs have the access, time, and budget to tinker with the new mode and find its limits. But it’s surely a sign that the race for models that can outreason humans has begun.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Now read the rest of The Algorithm</h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Deeper learning</strong></h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><strong>Chatbots can persuade people to stop believing in conspiracy theories</strong></strong></h4>



<p>Researchers believe they’ve uncovered a new tool for combating false conspiracy theories: AI chatbots. Researchers from MIT Sloan and Cornell University found that chatting about a conspiracy theory with a large language model (LLM) reduced people’s belief in it by about 20%—even among participants who claimed that their beliefs were important to their identity.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Why this matters:</strong> The findings could represent an important step forward in how we engage with and educate people who espouse such baseless theories, says Yunhao (Jerry) Zhang, a postdoc fellow affiliated with the Psychology of Technology Institute who studies AI’s impacts on society. “They show that with the help of large language models, we can—I wouldn’t say solve it, but we can at least mitigate this problem,” he says. “It points out a way to make society better.” <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103930/chatbots-can-persuade-people-to-stop-believing-in-conspiracy-theories/">Read more from Rhiannon Williams here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bits and bytes</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Google’s new tool lets large language models fact-check their responses</strong></p>



<p>Called DataGemma, it uses two methods to help LLMs check their responses against reliable data and cite their sources more transparently to users. (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103926/googles-new-tool-lets-large-language-models-fact-check-their-responses/">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>Meet the radio-obsessed civilian shaping Ukraine’s drone defense&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Since Russia’s invasion, Serhii “Flash” Beskrestnov has become an influential, if sometimes controversial, force—sharing expert advice and intel on the ever-evolving technology that’s taken over the skies. His work may determine the future of Ukraine, and wars far beyond it. (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103833/ukraine-russia-drone-war-flash-radio-serhii-beskrestnov-social-media/">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>Tech companies have joined a White House commitment to prevent AI-generated sexual abuse imagery</strong></p>



<p>The pledges, signed by firms like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Microsoft, aim to “curb the creation of image-based sexual abuse.” The companies promise to set limits on what models will generate and to remove nude images from training data sets where possible.&nbsp; (<a href="https://fortune.com/2024/09/13/openai-anthropic-and-microsoft-white-house-commitment-to-prevent-ai-deepfakes-sexual-abuse/">Fortune</a>)</p>



<p><strong>OpenAI is now valued at $150 billion</strong></p>



<p>The valuation arose out of talks it’s currently engaged in to raise $6.5 billion. Given that OpenAI is becoming increasingly costly to operate, and could lose as much as $5 billion this year, it’s tricky to see how it all adds up. (<a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/why-openai-could-lose-5-billion-this-year?rc=e9y5ks">The Information</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1104004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google is funding an AI-powered satellite constellation that will spot wildfires faster</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/16/1103962/google-is-funding-an-ai-powered-satellite-constellation-that-will-spot-wildfires-faster/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Temple]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate change and energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early next year, Google and its partners plan to launch the first in a series of satellites that together would provide close-up, frequently refreshed images of wildfires around the world, offering data that could help firefighters battle blazes more rapidly, effectively, and safely. The online search giant’s nonprofit and research arms have collaborated with the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Early next year, Google and its partners plan to launch the first in a series of satellites that together would provide close-up, frequently refreshed images of wildfires around the world, offering data that could help firefighters battle blazes more rapidly, effectively, and safely.</p>



<p>The online search giant’s nonprofit and research arms have collaborated with the Moore Foundation, the Environmental Defense Fund, the satellite company Muon Space, and others to deploy 52 satellites equipped with custom-developed sensors over the coming years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The FireSat satellites will be able to spot fires as small as 5 by 5 meters (16 by 16 feet) on any speck of the globe. Once the full constellation is in place, the system should be capable of updating those images about every 20 minutes, the group says.</p>



<p>Those capabilities together would mark a significant upgrade over what’s available from the satellites that currently provide data to fire agencies. Generally, they can provide either high-resolution images that aren’t updated rapidly enough to track fires closely or frequently refreshed images that are relatively low-resolution.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.earthfirealliance.org/">Earth Fire Alliance</a> collaboration will also leverage Google’s <a href="https://sites.research.google/gr/wildfires/">AI wildfire tools</a>, which have been trained to detect early indications of wildfires and track their progression, to draw additional insights from the data.</p>





<p>The images and analysis will be provided free to fire agencies around the world, helping to improve understanding of where fires are, where they’re moving, and how hot they’re burning. The information could help agencies stamp out small fires before they turn into raging infernos, place limited firefighting resources where they’ll do the most good, and evacuate people along the safest paths.</p>



<p>“In the satellite image of the Earth, a lot of things can be mistaken for a fire: a glint, a hot roof, smoke from another fire,” says Chris Van Arsdale, climate and energy research lead at Google Research and chairman of the Earth Fire Alliance. “Detecting fires becomes a game of looking for needles in a world of haystacks. Solving this will enable first responders to act quickly and precisely when a fire is detected.”</p>



<p>Some details of FireSat were <a href="https://www.muonspace.com/press/muon-space-and-earth-fire-alliance-unveil-firesat-constellation-a-revolutionary-space-mission-to-transform-global-wildfire-response">unveiled</a> <a href="https://www.earthfirealliance.org/news">earlier this year</a>. But the organizations involved will announce additional information about their plans today, including the news that Google.org, the company’s charitable arm, has provided $13 million to the program and that the inaugural launch is scheduled to occur next year.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Reducing the fog of war</h3>



<p>The news comes as <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2024/09/10/california-fires-update-trabuco-canyon-airport-orange-county/">large fires rage</a> across millions of acres in the western US, putting people and property at risk. The blazes include the Line Fire in Southern California, the Shoe Fly Fire in central Oregon, and the Davis Fire south of Reno, Nevada.</p>



<p>Wildfires have become more <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abc0020">frequent, extreme, and dangerous</a> in recent decades. That, in part, is a consequence of climate change: Rising temperatures suck the moisture from trees, shrubs, and grasses. But fires increasingly contribute to global warming as well. A recent <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/canada-wildfire-emissions">study</a> found that the fires that scorched millions of acres across Canada last year pumped out 3 billion tons of carbon dioxide, four times the annual pollution produced by the airline industry.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-wildfire.jpg?w=1920" alt="" class="wp-image-1103968" srcset="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-wildfire.jpg 1920w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-wildfire.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-wildfire.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-wildfire.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><div class="image-credit">GOOGLE</div>
</figure>
</div>


<p>Humans have also increased fire risk by <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/09/17/1008473/wildfires-california-prescribed-burns-climate-change-forests/">suppressing natural fires</a> for decades, which has allowed fuel to build up in forests and grasslands, and by constructing communities on the edge of wilderness boundaries <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2019/07/11/238838/why-the-town-destroyed-by-californias-camp-fire-is-rebuilding/">without appropriate rules, materials, and safeguards</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Observers say that FireSat could play an important role in combating fires, both by enabling fire agencies to extinguish small ones before they grow into large ones and by informing effective strategies for battling them once they’re crossed that point.</p>



<p>“What these satellites will do is reduce the fog of war,” says Michael Wara, director of the climate and energy policy program at Stanford University’s Woods Institute for the Environment, who is focused on fire policy issues. “Like when a situation is really dynamic and very dangerous for firefighters and they’re trying to make decisions very quickly about whether to move in to defend structures or try to evacuate people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Wara serves on the advisory board of the Moore Foundation&#8217;s Wildfire Resilience Initiative.)<br><br>Some areas, like California, already <a href="https://www.gov.ca.gov/2024/07/10/governor-newsom-and-fire-officials-highlight-californias-wildfire-readiness-and-response/">have greater visibility</a> into the current state of fires or early signs of outbreaks, thanks to technology like Department of Defense satellites, remote camera networks, and planes, helicopters, and drones. But FireSat will be especially helpful for “countries that have less-well-resourced wildland fighting capability,” Wara adds.</p>



<p>Better images, more data, and AI will not be able to fully counter the increased fire dangers. Wara and other fire experts argue that regions need to use prescribed burns and other efforts to more aggressively reduce the buildup of fuel, rethink where and how we build communities in fire-prone areas, and do more to fund and support the work of firefighters on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sounding an earlier alarm for fires will only help reduce dangers when regions have, or develop, the added firefighting resources needed to combat the most dangerous ones quickly and effectively. Communities will also need to put in place better policies to determine what types of fires should be left to burn, and under what conditions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">‘A game changer’</h3>



<p><a href="https://cafiresafecouncil.org/staff/kate-dargan-marquis/">Kate Dargan Marquis</a>, a senior wildfire advisor to the Moore Foundation who previously served as state fire marshal for California, says she can “personally attest” to the difference that such tools will make to firefighters in the field.</p>



<p>“It is a game changer, especially as wildfires are becoming more extreme, more frequent, and more dangerous for everyone,” she says. “Information like this will make a lifesaving difference for firefighters and communities around the globe.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-Kate-Dargan-Former-Cal-State-Fire-Marshal-Senior-Advisor-Moore-Foundation.jpg?w=1920" alt="" class="wp-image-1103966" srcset="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-Kate-Dargan-Former-Cal-State-Fire-Marshal-Senior-Advisor-Moore-Foundation.jpg 1920w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-Kate-Dargan-Former-Cal-State-Fire-Marshal-Senior-Advisor-Moore-Foundation.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-Kate-Dargan-Former-Cal-State-Fire-Marshal-Senior-Advisor-Moore-Foundation.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/FireSat-Kate-Dargan-Former-Cal-State-Fire-Marshal-Senior-Advisor-Moore-Foundation.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Kate Dargan Marquis, senior advisor, Moore Foundation.</figcaption><div class="image-credit">GOOGLE</div>
</figure>
</div>


<p>Google Research developed the sensors for the satellite and tested them as well as the company’s AI fire detection models by conducting flights over controlled burns in California. Google intends to work with Earth Fire Alliance “to ensure AI can help make this data as useful as possible, and also that wildfire information is shared as widely as possible,” the company said.</p>



<p>Google’s Van Arsdale says that providing visual images of every incident around the world from start to finish will be enormously valuable to scientists studying wildfires and climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We can combine this data with Google’s existing models of the Earth to help advance our understanding of fire behavior and fire dynamics across all of Earth’s ecosystems,” he says. “All this together really has the potential to help mitigate the environmental and social impact of fire while also improving people’s health and safety.”</p>



<p>Specifically, it could improve assessments of fire risk, as well as our understanding of the most effective means of preventing or slowing the spread of fires. For instance, it could help communities determine where it would be most cost-effective to remove trees and underbrush.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Figuring out the best ways to conduct such interventions is another key goal of the program, given their high cost and the limited funds available for managing wildlands, says Genny Biggs, the program director for the Moore Foundation’s Wildfire Resilience Initiative.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The launch</h3>



<p>The idea for FireSat grew out of <a href="https://www.kiss.caltech.edu/workshops/wildfires/wildfires.html">a series of meetings</a> that began with <a href="https://www.moore.org/article-detail?newsUrlName=workshop-report-fire-immediate-response-system">a 2019 workshop</a> hosted by the Moore Foundation, which provided the first philanthropic funding for the program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first satellite, scheduled to be launched aboard a SpaceX rocket early next year, will be fully functional aside from some data transmission features. The goals of the “protoflight” mission include testing the onboard systems and the data they send back. The Earth Fire Alliance will work with a handful of early-adopter agencies to prepare for the next phases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The group intends to launch three fully operational satellites in 2026, with additional deployments in the years that follow. Muon Space will build and operate the satellites.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Agencies around the world should be able to receive hourly wildfire updates once about half of the constellation is operational, says Brian Collins, executive director of the Earth Fire Alliance. It hopes to launch all 52 satellites by around the end of this decade.</p>



<p>Each satellite is designed to last about five years, so the organization will eventually need to deploy 10 more each year to maintain the constellation.</p>



<p>The Earth Fire Alliance has secured about two-thirds of the funding it needs for the first phase of the program, which includes the first four launches. The organization will need to raise additional money from government agencies, international organizations, philanthropies, and other groups&nbsp; to deploy, maintain, and operate the full constellation. It estimates the total cost will exceed $400 million, which Collins notes “is 1/1000th of the economic losses due to extreme wildfires annually in the US alone.”</p>



<p>Asked if commercial uses of the data could also support the program, including potentially military ones, Collins said in an email: “Adjacent applications range from land use management and agriculture to risk management and industrial impact and mitigation.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“At the same time, we know that as large agencies and government agencies adopt FireSat data to support a broad public safety mandate, they may develop all-hazard, emergenc[y] management, and security related uses of data,” he added. “As long as opportunities are in balance with our charter to advance a global approach to wildfire and climate resilience, we welcome new ideas and applications of our data.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">‘Living with fire’</h3>



<p>A wide variety of startups have emerged in recent years promising to use technology to reduce the frequency and severity of wildfires—for example, by <a href="https://www.pano.ai/">installing cameras</a> and sensors in forests and grasslands, <a href="https://burnbot.com/">developing robots</a> to carry out controlled burns, <a href="https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/business-aviation/2023-10-09/rain-and-sikorsky-collaborate-autonomous-firefighting">deploying autonomous helicopters</a> that can drop suppressant, and harnessing AI to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/15/how-ai-is-revolutionising-how-firefighters-tackle-blazes-and-saving-lives">predict wildfire behavior</a> and <a href="https://www.vibrantplanet.net/">inform forest and fire management strategies</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So far, even with all these new tools, it’s still been difficult for communities to keep pace with the rising dangers.</p>



<p><a href="https://cafiresafecouncil.org/staff/kate-dargan-marquis/">Dargan Marquis</a>—who <a href="https://www.intterra.io/">founded</a> her own wildfire software company, Intterra—says she is confident the incidence of disastrous fires can be meaningfully reduced with programs like FireSat, along with other improved technologies and policies. But she says it’s likely to take decades to catch up with the growing risks, as the world continues warming up.</p>



<p>“We&#8217;re going to struggle in places like California, these Mediterranean climates around the world, while our technology and our capabilities and our inventions, etc., catch up with that level of the problem,” she says.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We can turn that corner,” she adds. “If we work together on a comprehensive strategy with the right data and a convincing plan over the next 50 years, I do think that by the end of the century, we absolutely can be living with fire.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Download: an AI safety hotline, and tech for farmers</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/16/1103975/the-download-an-ai-safety-hotline-and-tech-for-farmers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Download]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Why we need an AI safety hotline —Kevin Frazier is an assistant professor at St. Thomas University College of Law and senior research fellow in the Constitutional Studies Program at the University of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Why we need an AI safety hotline</strong></p>



<p><em>—Kevin Frazier is an assistant professor at St. Thomas University College of Law and senior research fellow in the Constitutional Studies Program at the University of Texas at Austin.</em></p>



<p>In the past couple of years, regulators have been caught off guard again and again as tech companies compete to launch ever more advanced AI models. As it stands, it seems there’s little anyone can do to delay or prevent the release of a model that poses excessive risks.</p>



<p>Existing measures to mitigate AI risks aren’t enough to protect us, so we need new approaches. One could be a kind of AI safety hotline tasked with expert volunteers. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/16/1103959/why-we-need-an-ai-safety-hotline/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read more about how the hotline could work</a>.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>African farmers are using private satellite data to improve crop yields</strong></p>



<p>In many developing countries, farming is impaired by lack of data. For centuries, farmers relied on native intelligence rooted in experience and hope.<br><br>Now, farmers in Africa are turning to technology to avoid cycles of heavy crop losses that could spell financial disaster. They’re partnering with EOS Data Analytics, a California-based provider of satellite imagery and data for precision farming, which allows them to track where or when specific spots needed attention on various farms—and even to anticipate weather warnings. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/28/1096743/african-farmers-space-satellite-data-crop-yields/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Orji Sunday</em></p>



<p><strong>This piece is from the </strong><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/magazines/the-next-125-years-issue/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>latest print issue</strong></a><strong> of MIT Technology Review, which is celebrating 125 years of the magazine! If you don’t already, </strong><a href="https://ter.li/125th-Live-Download"><strong>subscribe now to get 25% off </strong></a><strong>future copies once they land.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The must-reads</strong></p>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 TikTok is heading to court today </strong><br><em>An appeals court will hear whether the app should be banned in the US</em>. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/14/24243794/tiktok-ban-bytedance-court-oral-arguments-lawsuit-explainer">The Verge</a>)<br>+ <em>The app is fighting the potential ban, which would kick in early next year</em>. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/16/technology/tiktok-us-ban-court.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ The depressing truth behind US attempts to ban TikTok. (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/05/01/1091951/tiktok-ban-chinese-companies-political/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 China has made a chipmaking equipment breakthrough</strong><br>A new machine should lessen its reliance on suppliers sanctioned by the US. (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-16/china-claims-chipmaking-gear-advance-despite-tightening-us-curbs?srnd=phx-technology&amp;sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+ <em>What’s next in chips. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/05/13/1092319/whats-next-in-chips/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>3 OpenAI’s newest AI models could be used to create bioweapons</strong><br>The company itself has given its latest releases its highest safety warning to date. (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/37ba7236-2a64-4807-b1e1-7e21ee7d0914">FT</a> $)<br>+ <em>In theory, it could aid experts with reproducing a biological threat. </em>(<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/371827/openai-chatgpt-artificial-intelligence-ai-risk-strawberry">Vox</a>)<br>+ <em>To avoid AI doom, learn from nuclear safety. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/06/06/1074077/to-avoid-ai-doom-learn-from-nuclear-safety/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>4 Big Tech’s carbon footprint is likely way bigger than they say</strong><br>Like, 662% bigger. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/sep/15/data-center-gas-emissions-tech">The Guardian</a>)<br>+ <em>Google, Amazon and the problem with Big Tech’s climate claims.</em> (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/07/17/1095019/google-amazon-and-the-problem-with-big-techs-climate-claims/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>5 Donald Trump is launching a new crypto business</strong><br>He’s set to launch it during a livestream today. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/13/technology/donald-trump-cryptocurrency-business.html">NYT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>6 SpaceX’s private space mission has touched down safety on Earth<br></strong>The first commercial mission was a big success—and opened the doors for future non-government projects. (<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cn5zrv1xrego">BBC</a>)<br>+ <em>The crew reached a higher altitude than any human has traveled in 50 years. </em>(<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/15/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-splashdown-landing/index.html">CNN</a>)</p>



<p><strong>7 We need to stop building in the ocean<br></strong>It’s severely affecting the way marine life navigates. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2024/09/marine-animal-land-bridge-green-sawfish/679884/">The Atlantic</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>8 We’re still learning about the benefits of breast milk </strong><br>Its antimicrobial properties could help to treat cancer and other conditions. (<a href="https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2024/09/11/breast-milks-benefits-are-not-limited-to-babies?itm_source=parsely-api">Economist</a> $)<br>+ <em>Startups are racing to reproduce breast milk in the lab. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/18/1013247/biomilq-breast-milk-helaina-turtletree/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>9 What the future of food holds</strong><br>From robot chefs to healthier potatoes. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/biotech/whats-ahead-for-food-d227da62?mod=tech_lead_pos4">WSJ</a> $)<br>+ <em>Robot-packed meals are coming to the frozen-food aisle. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/07/11/1094850/robot-packed-meals-are-coming-to-the-frozen-food-aisle/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>10 Meet Silicon Valley’s seriously pampered pets <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f415.png" alt="🐕" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><br>Pet tech doesn&#8217;t come cheap. (<a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/what-silicon-valley-buys-to-spoil-its-pets?rc=e9y5ks">The Information</a> $)</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Quote of the day</strong></p>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>“Welcome back to planet Earth.”</strong></p>



<p>—The host of the live SpaceX broadcast tracking the return of the company’s Polaris Dawn crew greets their homecoming after five days in orbit, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/15/spacex-polaris-dawn-mission-spacewalk/">the Washington Post</a> reports.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The big story</strong></p>



<p><strong>The future of open source is still very much in flux</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/08/17/1077498/future-open-source/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*|SUBCLASS|*&amp;utm_content=*|DATE:m-d-Y|*"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdO0mJ2HqSlJzp7sJ7C94506IV3UOGKehR8fsH5rUqdX8KAlkg8x2RiATjSZ8KjF4r5_COlLOMEdjyC3vGd_ZTo6VZMFy1bcMs9PKIZrhyhaJYZk_0mxUJRWAb2J7gq09csAKYssEmfmacTHINtYhlHQWrv?key=BVL-w_M-Uz-IBxNxtQ5VGg" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/08/17/1077498/future-open-source/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"></a><strong>August 2023</strong></p>



<p>When Xerox donated a new laser printer to MIT in 1980, the company couldn’t have known that the machine would ignite a revolution.</p>



<p>While the early decades of software development generally ran on a culture of open access, this new printer ran on inaccessible proprietary software, much to the horror of Richard M. Stallman, then a 27-year-old programmer at the university.</p>



<p>A few years later, Stallman released GNU, an operating system designed to be a free alternative to one of the dominant operating systems at the time: Unix. The free-software movement was born, with a simple premise: for the good of the world, all code should be open.</p>



<p>Forty years later, tech companies are making billions on proprietary software, and much of the technology around us is inscrutable. But while Stallman’s movement may look like a failed experiment, the free and open-source software movement is not only alive and well; it has become a keystone of the tech industry. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/08/17/1077498/future-open-source/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Rebecca Ackermann</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></p>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction to brighten up your day. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/yannon_"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em></p>



<p>+ The Hotel California solo series continues, this time with a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZGeKogHKY/">very intense recorder edition</a> (thanks Niall!)<br>+ <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/why-the-avocado-should-have-gone-the-way-of-the-dodo-4976527/">Avocados</a> should be extinct!? Say it ain’t so!<br>+ This quick and easy <a href="https://www.thetakeout.com/1660627/use-canned-peaches-cobbler/">peach cobbler</a> recipe looks like an absolute treat. <br>+ Nothing but love for <a href="https://time.com/7021047/moo-deng-baby-pygmy-hippo-thailand-viral-cute-safety-concerns/">Moo Deng</a> the tiny viral baby hippo. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f99b.png" alt="🦛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103975</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why we need an AI safety hotline</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/16/1103959/why-we-need-an-ai-safety-hotline/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Frazier]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the past couple of years, regulators have been caught off guard again and again as tech companies compete to launch ever more advanced AI models. It’s only a matter of time before labs release another round of models that pose new regulatory challenges. We’re likely just weeks away, for example, from OpenAI’s release of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the past couple of years, regulators have been caught off guard again and again as tech companies compete to launch ever more advanced AI models. It’s only a matter of time before labs release another round of models that pose new regulatory challenges. We’re likely just weeks away, for example, from OpenAI’s release of ChatGPT-5, which promises to push AI capabilities further than ever before. As it stands, it seems there’s little anyone can do to delay or prevent the release of a model that poses excessive risks.<br><br>Testing AI models before they’re released is a common approach to mitigating certain risks, and it may help regulators weigh up the costs and benefits—and potentially block models from being released if they’re deemed too dangerous. But the accuracy and comprehensiveness of these tests leaves a lot to be desired. AI models may <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07358">“sandbag” the evaluation</a>—hiding some of their capabilities to avoid raising any safety concerns. The evaluations may also fail to reliably uncover the full set of risks posed by any one model. Evaluations likewise suffer from limited scope—current tests are unlikely to uncover all the risks that warrant further investigation. There’s also the question of who conducts the evaluations and how their biases may influence testing efforts. For those reasons, evaluations need to be used alongside other governance tools. </p>



<p>One such tool could be internal reporting mechanisms within the labs. Ideally, employees should feel empowered to regularly and fully share their AI safety concerns with their colleagues, and they should feel those colleagues can then be counted on to act on the concerns. However, there’s growing evidence that, far from being promoted, open criticism is becoming rarer in AI labs. Just three months ago, 13 former and current workers from OpenAI and other labs <a href="https://righttowarn.ai/">penned an open letter</a> expressing fear of retaliation if they attempt to disclose questionable corporate behaviors that fall short of breaking the law. </p>





<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How to sound the alarm</h3>



<p>In theory, external whistleblower protections could play a valuable role in the detection of AI risks. These could protect employees fired for disclosing corporate actions, and they could help make up for inadequate internal reporting mechanisms. Nearly <a href="https://whistleblower.org/in-the-news/techtarget-catastrophic-ai-risks-highlight-need-for-whistleblower-laws/">every state has a public policy exception</a> to at-will employment termination—in other words, terminated employees can seek recourse against their employers if they were retaliated against for calling out unsafe or illegal corporate practices. However, in practice this exception offers employees few assurances. <a href="https://scholarworks.law.ubalt.edu/all_fac/444/">Judges tend</a> to favor employers in whistleblower cases. The likelihood of AI labs’ surviving such suits seems particularly high given that society has yet to reach any sort of consensus as to what qualifies as unsafe AI development and deployment. </p>



<p>These and other shortcomings explain why the <a href="https://righttowarn.ai/">aforementioned 13 AI workers</a>, including ex-OpenAI employee William Saunders, called for a novel “right to warn.” Companies would have to offer employees an anonymous process for disclosing risk-related concerns to the lab’s board, a regulatory authority, and an independent third body made up of subject-matter experts. The ins and outs of this process have yet to be figured out, but it would presumably be a formal, bureaucratic mechanism. The board, regulator, and third party would all need to make a record of the disclosure. It’s likely that each body would then initiate some sort of investigation. Subsequent meetings and hearings also seem like a necessary part of the process. Yet if Saunders is to be taken at his word, what AI workers <em>really </em>want is something different.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When Saunders went on the <em>Big Technology Podcast</em> to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/what-the-ex-openai-safety-employees-are-worried-about/id1522960417?i=1000661018304">outline his ideal process</a> for sharing safety concerns, his focus was not on formal avenues for reporting established risks. Instead, he indicated a desire for some intermediate, informal step. He wants a chance to receive neutral, expert feedback on whether a safety concern is substantial enough to go through a “high stakes” process such as a right-to-warn system. Current government regulators, as Saunders says, could not serve that role.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For one thing, they likely lack the expertise to help an AI worker think through safety concerns. What’s more, few workers will pick up the phone if they know it&#8217;s a government official on the other end—that sort of call may be “very intimidating,” as Saunders himself said on the podcast. Instead, he envisages being able to call an expert to discuss his concerns. In an ideal scenario, he’d be told that the risk in question does not seem that severe or likely to materialize, freeing him up to return to whatever he was doing with more peace of mind. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Lowering the stakes</h3>



<p>What Saunders is asking for in this podcast isn’t a right to warn, then, as that suggests the employee is already convinced there’s unsafe or illegal activity afoot. What he’s really calling for is a gut check—an opportunity to verify whether a suspicion of unsafe or illegal behavior seems warranted. The stakes would be much lower, so the regulatory response could be lighter. The third party responsible for weighing up these gut checks could be a much more informal one. For example, AI PhD students, retired AI industry workers, and other individuals with AI expertise could volunteer for an AI safety hotline. They could be tasked with quickly and expertly discussing safety matters with employees via a confidential and anonymous phone conversation. Hotline volunteers would have familiarity with leading safety practices, as well as extensive knowledge of what options, such as right-to-warn mechanisms, may be available to the employee.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Saunders indicated, few employees will likely want to go from 0 to 100 with their safety concerns—straight from colleagues to the board or even a government body. They are much more likely to raise their issues if an intermediary, informal step is available. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Studying examples elsewhere </h3>



<p>The details of how precisely an AI safety hotline would work deserve more debate among AI community members, regulators, and civil society. For the hotline to realize its full potential, for instance, it may need some way to escalate the most urgent, verified reports to the appropriate authorities. How to ensure the confidentiality of hotline conversations is another matter that needs thorough investigation. How to recruit and retain volunteers is another key question. Given leading experts’ broad concern about AI risk, some may be willing to participate simply out of a desire to lend a hand. Should too few folks step forward, other incentives may be necessary. The essential first step, though, is acknowledging this missing piece in the puzzle of AI safety regulation. The next step is looking for models to emulate in building out the first AI hotline. </p>



<p>One place to start is with ombudspersons. Other industries have recognized the value of identifying these neutral, independent individuals as resources for evaluating the seriousness of employee concerns. <a href="https://abaombudsday.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/neutrality-a-guide-for-the-organizational-ombudsperson-_-gadlin-_-pino.pdf">Ombudspersons exist in academia</a>, nonprofits, and the private sector. The distinguishing attribute of these <a href="https://abaombudsday.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/neutrality-a-guide-for-the-organizational-ombudsperson-_-gadlin-_-pino.pdf">individuals and their staffers is neutrality</a>—they have no incentive to favor one side or the other, and thus they’re more likely to be trusted by all. A glance at the use of ombudspersons in the federal government shows that when they are available, issues may be raised and resolved sooner than they would be otherwise.</p>



<p>This concept is relatively new. The US Department of Commerce <a href="https://www.acus.gov/sites/default/files/documents/PART%202_Research%20Final%20%2011.14.16%20%28ACUS%29.pdf">established the first federal ombudsman</a> in 1971. The office was tasked with helping citizens resolve disputes with the agency and investigate agency actions. Other agencies, including the Social Security Administration and the Internal Revenue Service, soon followed suit. <a href="https://www.acus.gov/sites/default/files/documents/PART%202_Research%20Final%20%2011.14.16%20%28ACUS%29.pdf">A retrospective review</a> of these early efforts concluded that effective ombudspersons can meaningfully improve citizen-government relations. On the whole, ombudspersons were associated with an uptick in voluntary compliance with regulations and cooperation with the government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An AI ombudsperson or safety hotline would surely have different tasks and staff from an ombudsperson in a federal agency. Nevertheless, the general concept is worthy of study by those advocating safeguards in the AI industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A right to warn may play a role in getting AI safety concerns aired, but we need to set up more intermediate, informal steps as well. An AI safety hotline is low-hanging regulatory fruit. A pilot made up of volunteers could be organized in relatively short order and provide an immediate outlet for those, like Saunders, who merely want a sounding board.</p>



<p><em>Kevin Frazier is an assistant professor at St. Thomas University College of Law and senior research fellow in the Constitutional Studies Program at the University of Texas at Austin.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103959</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Download: conspiracy-debunking chatbots, and fact-checking AI</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/13/1103952/the-download-conspiracy-debunking-chatbots-and-fact-checking-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Download]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Chatbots can persuade people to stop believing in conspiracy theories The internet has made it easier than ever before to encounter and spread conspiracy theories. And while some are harmless, others can be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Chatbots can persuade people to stop believing in conspiracy theories</strong></p>



<p>The internet has made it easier than ever before to encounter and spread conspiracy theories. And while some are harmless, others can be deeply damaging, sowing discord and even leading to unnecessary deaths.<br><br>Now, researchers believe they’ve uncovered a new tool for combating false conspiracy theories: AI chatbots. Researchers from MIT Sloan and Cornell University found that chatting about a conspiracy theory with a large language model (LLM) reduced people’s belief in it by about 20%—even among participants who claimed that their beliefs were important to their identity<br><br>The findings could represent an important step forward in how we engage with and educate people who espouse baseless theories. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103930/chatbots-can-persuade-people-to-stop-believing-in-conspiracy-theories/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Rhiannon Williams</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Google’s new tool lets large language models fact-check their responses</strong></p>



<p><strong>The news: </strong>Google is releasing a tool called DataGemma that it hopes will help to reduce problems caused by AI &#8216;hallucinating’, or making incorrect claims. It uses two methods to help large language models fact-check their responses against reliable data and cite their sources more transparently to users. </p>



<p><strong>What next:</strong> If it works as hoped, it could be a real boon for Google’s plan to embed AI deeper into its search engine. But it comes with a host of caveats. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103926/googles-new-tool-lets-large-language-models-fact-check-their-responses/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—James O&#8217;Donnell</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Neuroscientists and architects are using this enormous laboratory to make buildings better</strong></p>



<p>Have you ever found yourself lost in a building that felt impossible to navigate? Thoughtful building design should center on the people who will be using those buildings. But that’s no mean feat.<br><br>A design that works for some people might not work for others. People have different minds and bodies, and varying wants and needs. So how can we factor them all in?</p>



<p>To answer that question, neuroscientists and architects are joining forces at an enormous laboratory in East London—one that allows researchers to build simulated worlds. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/13/1103935/neuroscientists-architects-enormous-laboratory-make-buildings-better/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Jessica Hamzelou</em></p>



<p><strong>This story is from The Checkup, our weekly biotech and health newsletter. </strong><a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/biotech-the-checkup/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>Sign up</strong></a><strong> to receive it in your inbox every Thursday.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The must-reads</strong></p>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 OpenAI has released an AI model with ‘reasoning’ capabilities</strong><br>It claims it’s a step toward its broader goal of human-like artificial intelligence. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/12/24242439/openai-o1-model-reasoning-strawberry-chatgpt">The Verge</a>)<br>+ <em>It could prove particularly useful for coders and math tutors. </em>(<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/technology/openai-chatgpt-math.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>Why does AI being good at math matter? </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/01/23/1086944/why-does-ai-being-good-at-math-matter/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 Microsoft wants to lead the way in climate innovation</strong><br>While simultaneously selling AI to fossil fuel companies. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/09/microsoft-ai-oil-contracts/679804/">The Atlantic</a> $)<br>+ <em>Google, Amazon and the problem with Big Tech’s climate claims. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/07/17/1095019/google-amazon-and-the-problem-with-big-techs-climate-claims/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>3 The FDA has approved Apple’s AirPods as hearing aids</strong><br>Just two years after the body first approved over-the-counter aids. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/12/fda-approval-apple-airpod-hearing-aid/">WP</a> $)<br>+ <em>It could fundamentally shift how people access hearing-enhancing devices. </em>(<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/12/24241960/apple-airpods-pro-2-otc-hearing-aid-health-industry">The Verge</a>)</p>



<p><strong>4 Parents aren’t using Meta’s child safety controls </strong><br>So claims Nick Clegg, the company’s global affairs chief. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/sep/12/parental-controls-facebook-instagram-meta-nick-clegg">The Guardian</a>)<br>+ <em>Many tech execs restrict their own childrens’ exposure to technology. </em>(<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/09/social-media-lgbtq-teens-harms/679798/">The Atlantic</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>5 How AI is turbo boosting legal action</strong><br>Especially when it comes to mass litigation. (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/8a3fcad2-f70f-4764-8669-acaa4164eee8">FT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>6 Low-income Americans were targeted by false ads for free cash<br></strong>Some victims had their health insurance plans changed without their consent. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/social-media-ads-health-insurance-scams-37d1ecfa?mod=hp_lead_pos6">WSJ</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>7 Inside the stratospheric rise of the ‘medical’ beverage<br></strong>Promising us everything from glowier skin to increased energy. (<a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/371564/functional-beverages-tonics-teas-soda-prebiotic-medicine">Vox</a>)</p>



<p><strong>8 Japan’s police force is heading online<br></strong>Cybercrime is booming, as criminal activity in the real world drops. (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-13/japan-to-shift-away-from-24-7-police-outposts-as-crime-moves-to-cyberspace?srnd=phx-technology&amp;sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>9 AI can replicate your late loved ones’ handwriting <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/270d.png" alt="✍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><br>For some, it’s a touching reminder of someone they loved. (<a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/09/my-dead-father-is-writing-me-notes-again/">Ars Technica</a>)<br>+ <em>Technology that lets us “speak” to our dead relatives has arrived. Are we ready? </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/10/18/1061320/digital-clones-of-dead-people/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>10 Crypto creators are resorting to dangerous stunts for attention</strong><br>Don’t try this at home. (<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/people-on-fire-punched-pump-crypto-coins/">Wired</a> $)</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Quote of the day</strong></p>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>“You can&#8217;t have a conversation with James the AI bot. He&#8217;s not going to show up at events.”</strong></p>



<p>—A former reporter for Garden Island, a local newspaper in Hawaii, dismisses the company’s decision to invest in new AI-generated presenters for its website, <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/an-ai-bot-named-james-has-my-old-local-news-job/">Wired</a> reports.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The big story</strong></p>



<p><strong>AI hype is built on high test scores. Those tests are flawed.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/08/30/1078670/large-language-models-arent-people-lets-stop-testing-them-like-they-were/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*|SUBCLASS|*&amp;utm_content=*|DATE:m-d-Y|*"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcZu58AZeHsoU7OfHdQWbBpq6FFZQbwd2lE4hFtcr62xzT4YVeP-v5cYJJBGxXDqv_Lpu0Tx-pkYb64gH_Sev7rlbAP_M4SCe13_3J-g0-5kEcGeLVa4A3g5PEjhGeOPonjteaNSsCvjgoQhhcCAvPmDVrU?key=A5axj7mKPXecNSJ36Je1aQ" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p><strong>August 2023<br><br></strong>In the past few years, multiple researchers claim to have shown that large language models can pass cognitive tests designed for humans, from working through problems step by step, to guessing what other people are thinking.<br><br>These kinds of results are feeding a hype machine predicting that these machines will soon come for white-collar jobs. But there’s a problem: There’s little agreement on what those results really mean. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/08/30/1078670/large-language-models-arent-people-lets-stop-testing-them-like-they-were/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.<br> <br><em>—William Douglas Heaven</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></p>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction to brighten up your day. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/yannon_"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em></p>



<p>+ It’s almost time for Chinese <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/travel/the-rebellious-history-of-mooncakes-the-note-passing-dessert-that-liberated-china-180985046/">mooncake</a> madness to celebrate the Moon Festival! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f96e.png" alt="🥮" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br>+ Pearl the Wonder Horse isn’t just a therapy animal—she’s also an accomplished <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-6zz0PRoot/?igsh=MXZnN2NtbWhjcnFpYQ%3D%3D">keyboardist</a>.<br>+ We love you <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/peter-dinklage-the-thicket-game-of-thrones-1235101172/">Peter Dinklage</a>!<br>+ Money for Nothing sounds even better on a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZGeKtySBn/">lute</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103952</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neuroscientists and architects are using this enormous laboratory to make buildings better</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/13/1103935/neuroscientists-architects-enormous-laboratory-make-buildings-better/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Hamzelou]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotechnology and health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Checkup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever found yourself lost in a building that felt impossible to navigate? Thoughtful building design should center on the people who will be using those buildings. But that’s no mean feat. It’s not just about navigation, either. Just think of an office that left you feeling sleepy or unproductive, or perhaps a health&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Have you ever found yourself lost in a building that felt impossible to navigate? Thoughtful building design should center on the people who will be using those buildings. But that’s no mean feat.</p>



<p>It’s not just about navigation, either. Just think of an office that left you feeling sleepy or unproductive, or perhaps a health center that had a less-than-reviving atmosphere. A design that works for some people might not work for others. People have different minds and bodies, and varying wants and needs. So how can we factor them all in?</p>



<p><strong>To answer that question, neuroscientists and architects are joining forces at an enormous laboratory in East London—one that allows researchers to build simulated worlds.</strong> In this lab, scientists can control light, temperature, and sound. They can create the illusion of a foggy night, or the tinkle of morning birdsong.</p>





<p>And they can study how volunteers respond to these environments, whether they be simulations of grocery stores, hospitals, pedestrian crossings, or schools. That’s how I found myself wandering around a fake art gallery, wearing a modified baseball cap with a sensor that tracked my movements.</p>



<p><strong>I first visited the Person-Environment-Activity Research Lab, referred to as PEARL, back in July.</strong> I’d been chatting to Hugo Spiers, a neuroscientist based at University College London, about <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/06/28/1094417/how-ai-video-games-can-help-reveal-the-mysteries-of-the-human-mind/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">the use of video games to study how people navigate</a>. Spiers had told me he was working on another project: exploring how people navigate a lifelike environment, and how they respond during evacuations (which, depending on the situation, could be a matter of life or death).</p>



<p>For their research, Spiers and his colleagues set up what they call a “mocked-up art gallery” within PEARL. The center in its entirety is pretty huge as labs go, measuring around 100 meters in length and 40 meters across, with 10-meter-high ceilings in places. There’s no other research center in the world like this, Spiers told me.</p>



<p><strong>The gallery setup looked a little like a maze from above, with a pathway created out of hanging black sheets. </strong>The exhibits themselves were videos of dramatic artworks that had been created by UCL students.</p>



<p>When I visited in July, Spiers and his colleagues were running a small pilot study to trial their setup. As a volunteer participant, I was handed a numbered black cap with a square board on top, marked with a large QR code. This code would be tracked by cameras above and around the gallery. The cap also carried a sensor, transmitting radio signals to devices around the maze that could pinpoint my location within a range of 15 centimeters.</p>





<p><strong>At first, all the volunteers (most of whom seemed to be students) were asked to explore the gallery as we would any other.</strong> I meandered around, watching the videos, and eavesdropping on the other volunteers, who were chatting about their research and upcoming dissertation deadlines. It all felt pretty pleasant and calm.</p>



<p>That feeling dissipated in the second part of the experiment, when we were each given a list of numbers, told that each one referred to a numbered screen, and informed that we had to visit all the screens in the order in which they appeared on our lists. “Good luck, everybody,” Spiers said.</p>



<p><strong>Suddenly everyone seemed to be rushing around, slipping past each other and trying to move quickly while avoiding collisions. </strong>“It’s all got a bit frantic, hasn’t it?” I heard one volunteer comment as I accidentally bumped into another. I hadn’t managed to complete the task by the time Spiers told us the experiment was over. As I walked to the exit, I noticed that some people were visibly out of breath.</p>



<p>The full study took place on Wednesday, September 11. This time, there were around 100 volunteers (I wasn’t one of them). And while almost everyone was wearing a modified baseball cap, some had more complicated gear, including <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/22/1097185/tech-brainwaves-100-years/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">EEG caps to measure brainwaves</a>, or caps that use near-infrared spectroscopy to measure blood flow in the brain. Some people were even wearing eye-tracking devices that monitored which direction they were looking.</p>



<p><strong>“We will do something quite remarkable today,” Spiers told the volunteers, staff, and observers as the experiment started.</strong> Taking such detailed measurements from so many individuals in such a setting represented “a world first,” he said.</p>



<p><strong>I have to say that being an observer was much more fun than being a participant. </strong>Gone was the stress of remembering instructions and speeding around a maze. Here in my seat, I could watch as the data collected from the cameras and sensors was projected onto a screen. The volunteers, represented as squiggly colored lines, made their way through the gallery in a way that reminded me of the game Snake.</p>



<p>The study itself was similar to the pilot study, although this time the volunteers were given additional tasks. At one point, they were given an envelope with the name of a town or city in it, and asked to find others in the group who had been given the same one. It was fascinating to see the groups form. Some had the names of destination cities like Bangkok, while others had been assigned fairly nondescript English towns like Slough, made famous as the setting of the British television series <em>The Office</em>. At another point, the volunteers were asked to evacuate the gallery from the nearest exit.</p>





<p><strong>The data collected in this study represents something of a treasure trove for researchers like Spiers and his colleagues.</strong> The team is hoping to learn more about how people navigate a space, and whether they move differently if they are alone or in a group. How do friends and strangers interact, and does this depend on whether they have certain types of material to bond over? How do people respond to evacuations—will they take the nearest exit as directed, or will they run on autopilot to the exit they used to enter the space in the first place?</p>



<p>All this information is valuable to neuroscientists like Spiers, but it’s also useful to architects like his colleague Fiona Zisch, who is based at UCL’s Bartlett School of Architecture. “We do really care about how people feel about the places we design for them,” Zisch tells me. The findings can guide not only the construction of new buildings, but also efforts to modify and redesign existing ones.</p>



<p><strong>PEARL was built in 2021 and has already been used to help engineers, scientists, and architects explore how neurodivergent people use grocery stores, and the ideal lighting to use for pedestrian crossings, for example. </strong>Zisch herself is passionate about creating equitable spaces—particularly for health and education—that everyone can make use of in the best possible way.</p>



<p>In the past, models used in architecture have been developed with typically built, able-bodied men in mind. “But not everyone is a 6&#8217;2&#8243; male with a briefcase,” Zisch tells me. Age, gender, height, and a range of physical and psychological factors can all influence how a person will use a building. “We want to improve not just the space, but the experience of the space,” says Zisch. Good architecture isn’t just about creating stunning features; it’s about subtle adaptations that might not even be noticeable to most people, she says.</p>



<p>The art gallery study is just the first step for researchers like Zisch and Spiers, who plan to explore other aspects of neuroscience and architecture in more simulated environments at PEARL. The team won’t have results for a while yet. But it’s a fascinating start. Watch this space.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Now read the rest of The Checkup</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Read more from MIT Technology Review&#8217;s archive</h3>



<p><strong>Brain-monitoring technology has come a long way, and tech designed to read our minds and probe our memories is already being used.</strong> Futurist and legal ethicist Nita Farahany explained <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/03/17/1069897/tech-read-your-mind-probe-your-memories/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">why we need laws to protect our cognitive liberty</a> in a previous edition of The Checkup.</p>



<p><strong>Listening in on the brain can reveal surprising insights into how this mysterious organ works.</strong> One team of neuroscientists found that <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/02/07/1067951/brains-week-order-chaos/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">our brains seem to oscillate between states of order and chaos</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Last year, <em>MIT Technology Review</em> published <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/magazines/the-design-issue/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">our design issue of the magazine</a>.</strong> If you’re curious, <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/02/22/1068297/design-definition-needs-change/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">this piece on the history and future of the word “design,”</a> by Nicholas de Monchaux, head of architecture at MIT, might be a good place to start</p>



<p><strong>Design covers much more than buildings, of course.</strong> <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/02/10/1067838/prosthetics-that-break-the-mold/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">Designers are creating new ways for users of prosthetic devices to feel more comfortable in their own skin</a>—some of which have third thumbs, spikes, or “superhero skins.”</p>



<p><strong>Achim Menges is an architect creating what he calls “self-shaping” structures with wood, which can twist and curve with changes in humidity.</strong> His approach is a low-energy way to make complex curved architectures, <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/06/24/1093513/achim-menges-architect-wood-buildings-sustainability/?utm_source=the_checkup&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_checkup.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_content=09-12-24">Menges told John Wiegand</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">From around the web</h3>



<p><strong>Scientists are meant to destroy research samples of the poliovirus, as part of efforts to eradicate the disease it causes. </strong>But lab leaks of the virus may be more common than we’d like to think. (<a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/poliovirus-infected-chinese-child-2014-may-have-leaked-lab">Science</a>)</p>



<p><strong>Neurofeedback allows people to watch their own brain activity in real time, and learn to control it.</strong> It could be a useful way to combat the impacts of stress. (<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0166223624001504">Trends in Neurosciences</a>)</p>



<p><strong>Microbes, some of which cause disease in people, can travel over a thousand miles on wind, researchers have shown.</strong> Some appear to be able to survive their journey. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/article/2024/sep/09/pathogenic-microbes-carried-vast-distances-by-winds">The Guardian</a>)</p>



<p><strong>Is the X chromosome involved in Alzheimer’s disease?</strong> A study of over a million people suggests so. (<a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaneurology/fullarticle/2823160">JAMA Neurology</a>)</p>



<p><strong>A growing number of men are paying thousands of dollars a year for testosterone therapies that are meant to improve their physical performance. </strong>But some are left with enlarged breasts, shrunken testicles, blood clots, and infertility. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/testosterone-clinics-telehealth-steroids-474835d5">The Wall Street Journal</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chatbots can persuade people to stop believing in conspiracy theories</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103930/chatbots-can-persuade-people-to-stop-believing-in-conspiracy-theories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The internet has made it easier than ever before to encounter and spread conspiracy theories. And while some are harmless, others can be deeply damaging, sowing discord and even leading to unnecessary deaths. Now, researchers believe they’ve uncovered a new tool for combating false conspiracy theories: AI chatbots. Researchers from MIT Sloan and Cornell University&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The internet has made it easier than ever before to encounter and spread conspiracy theories. And while some are harmless, others can be deeply damaging, sowing discord and even leading to unnecessary <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/07/1095762/covid-conspiracies-hiv-aids-denial-public-health/">deaths</a>.</p>



<p>Now, researchers believe they’ve uncovered a new tool for combating false conspiracy theories: AI chatbots. Researchers from MIT Sloan and Cornell University found that chatting about a conspiracy theory with a large language model (LLM) reduced people’s belief in it by about 20%—even among participants who claimed that their beliefs were important to their identity. The research is published today in the journal <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.adq1814"><em>Science</em></a>.</p>



<p>The findings could represent an important step forward in how we engage with and educate people who espouse such baseless theories, says Yunhao (Jerry) Zhang, a postdoc fellow affiliated with the Psychology of Technology Institute who studies AI’s impacts on society.</p>



<p>“They show that with the help of large language models, we can—I wouldn’t say solve it, but we can at least mitigate this problem,” he says. “It points out a way to make society better.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Few interventions have been proven to change conspiracy theorists’ minds, says Thomas Costello, a research affiliate at MIT Sloan and the lead author of the study. Part of what makes it so hard is that different people tend to latch on to different parts of a theory. This means that while presenting certain bits of factual evidence may work on one believer, there’s no guarantee that it’ll prove effective on another.</p>



<p>That’s where AI models come in, he says. “They have access to a ton of information across diverse topics, and they’ve been trained on the internet. Because of that, they have the ability to tailor factual counterarguments to particular conspiracy theories that people believe.”</p>



<p>The team tested its method by asking 2,190 crowdsourced workers to participate in text conversations with GPT-4 Turbo, OpenAI’s latest large language model.</p>



<p>Participants were asked to share details about a conspiracy theory they found credible, why they found it compelling, and any evidence they felt supported it. These answers were used to tailor responses from the chatbot, which the researchers had prompted to be as persuasive as possible.</p>





<p></p>



<p>Participants were also asked to indicate how confident they were that their conspiracy theory was true, on a scale from 0 (definitely false) to 100 (definitely true), and then rate how important the theory was to their understanding of the world. Afterwards, they entered into three rounds of conversation with the AI bot. The researchers chose three to make sure they could collect enough substantive dialogue.</p>



<p>After each conversation, participants were asked the same rating questions. The researchers followed up with all the participants 10 days after the experiment, and then two months later, to assess whether their views had changed following the conversation with the AI bot. The participants reported a 20% reduction of belief in their chosen conspiracy theory on average, suggesting that talking to the bot had fundamentally changed some people’s minds.</p>



<p>“Even in a lab setting, 20% is a large effect on changing people’s beliefs,” says Zhang. “It might be weaker in the real world, but even 10% or 5% would still be very substantial.”</p>



<p>The authors sought to safeguard against AI models’ tendency to make up information—known as <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/06/18/1093440/what-causes-ai-hallucinate-chatbots/">hallucinating</a>—by employing a professional fact-checker to evaluate the accuracy of 128 claims the AI had made. Of these, 99.2% were found to be true, while 0.8% were deemed misleading. None were found to be completely false.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One explanation for this high degree of accuracy is that a lot has been written about conspiracy theories on the internet, making them very well represented in the model’s training data, says David G. Rand, a professor at MIT Sloan who also worked on the project. The adaptable nature of GPT-4 Turbo means it could easily be connected to different platforms for users to interact with in the future, he adds.</p>



<p>“You could imagine just going to conspiracy forums and inviting people to do their own research by debating the chatbot,” he says. “Similarly, social media could be hooked up to LLMs to post corrective responses to people sharing conspiracy theories, or we could buy Google search ads against conspiracy-related search terms like ‘Deep State.’”</p>



<p>The research upended the authors’ preconceived notions about how receptive people were to solid evidence debunking not only conspiracy theories, but also other beliefs that are not rooted in good-quality information, says Gordon Pennycook, an associate professor at Cornell University who also worked on the project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“People were remarkably responsive to evidence. And that’s really important,” he says. “Evidence does matter.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103930</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google’s new tool lets large language models fact-check their responses</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103926/googles-new-tool-lets-large-language-models-fact-check-their-responses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James O'Donnell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As long as chatbots have been around, they have made things up. Such “hallucinations” are an inherent part of how AI models work. However, they’re a big problem for companies betting big on AI, like Google, because they make the responses it generates unreliable.&#160; Google is releasing a tool today to address the issue. Called&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As long as chatbots have been around, they have made things up. Such “hallucinations” are an <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/06/18/1093440/what-causes-ai-hallucinate-chatbots/">inherent part</a> of how AI models work. However, they’re a big problem for companies betting big on AI, like Google, because they make the responses it generates unreliable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Google is releasing a tool today to address the issue. Called DataGemma, it uses two methods to help large language models fact-check their responses against reliable data and cite their sources more transparently to users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first of the two methods is called Retrieval-Interleaved Generation (RIG), which acts as a sort of fact-checker. If a user prompts the model with a question—like “Has the use of renewable energy sources increased in the world?”—the model will come up with a “first draft” answer. Then RIG identifies what portions of the draft answer could be checked against Google’s <a href="https://datacommons.org/">Data Commons</a>, a massive repository of data and statistics from reliable sources like the United Nations or the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Next, it runs those checks and replaces any incorrect original guesses with correct facts. It also cites its sources to the user.</p>



<p>The second method, which is commonly used in other large language models, is called Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). Consider a prompt like “What progress has Pakistan made against global health goals?” In response, the model examines which data in the Data Commons could help it answer the question, such as information about access to safe drinking water, hepatitis B immunizations, and life expectancies. With those figures in hand, the model then builds its answer on top of the data and cites its sources.</p>



<p>“Our goal here was to use Data Commons to enhance the reasoning of LLMs by grounding them in real-world statistical data that you could source back to where you got it from,” says Prem Ramaswami, head of Data Commons at Google. Doing so, he says, will “create more trustable, reliable AI.”</p>





<p>It is only available to researchers for now, but Ramaswami says access could widen further after more testing. If it works as hoped, it could be a real boon for Google’s plan to embed AI deeper into its search engine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, it comes with a host of caveats. First, the usefulness of the methods is limited by whether the relevant data is in the Data Commons, which is more of a data repository than an encyclopedia. It can tell you the GDP of Iran, but it’s unable to confirm the date of the First Battle of Fallujah or when Taylor Swift released her most recent single. In fact, Google’s researchers found that with about 75% of the test questions, the RIG method was unable to obtain any usable data from the Data Commons. And even if helpful data is indeed housed in the Data Commons, the model doesn’t always formulate the right questions to find it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, there is the question of accuracy. When testing the RAG method, researchers found that the model gave incorrect answers 6% to 20% of the time. Meanwhile, the RIG method pulled the correct stat from Data Commons only about 58% of the time (though that’s a big improvement over the 5% to 17% accuracy rate of Google’s large language models when they’re <em>not</em> pinging Data Commons).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ramaswami says DataGemma’s accuracy will improve as it gets trained on more and more data. The initial version has been trained on only about 700 questions, and fine-tuning the model required his team to manually check each individual fact it generated. To further improve the model, the team plans to increase that data set from hundreds of questions to millions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103926</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Download: Ukraine&#8217;s drone defenses, and today&#8217;s climate heroes</title>
		<link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103921/the-download-ukraines-drone-defenses-and-todays-climate-heroes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Download]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1103921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Meet the radio-obsessed civilian shaping Ukraine’s drone defense Drones have come to define the brutal conflict in Ukraine that has now dragged on for more than two and a half years. And most&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology</em>.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Meet the radio-obsessed civilian shaping Ukraine’s drone defense</strong></p>



<p>Drones have come to define the brutal conflict in Ukraine that has now dragged on for more than two and a half years. And most rely on radio communications—a technology that Serhii “Flash” Beskrestnov has obsessed over since childhood.<br><br>While Flash is now a civilian, the former officer has still taken it upon himself to inform his country’s defense in all matters related to radio. Once a month, he studies the skies for Russian radio transmissions and tries to learn about the problems facing troops in the fields and in the trenches.</p>



<p>In this race for survival—as each side constantly tries to best the other, only to start all over again when the other inevitably catches up—Ukrainian soldiers need to develop creative solutions, and fast. As Ukraine’s wartime radio guru, Flash may just be one of their best hopes for doing that. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103833/ukraine-russia-drone-war-flash-radio-serhii-beskrestnov-social-media/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Charlie Metcalfe</em></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Meet 2024’s climate innovators under 35</strong></p>



<p>One way to know where a field is going? Take a look at what the sharpest new innovators are working on.</p>



<p>Good news for all of us: MIT Technology Review’s list of <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/innovators-under-35/2024/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">35 Innovators Under 35</a> just dropped. A decent number of the people who made the list are working in fields that touch climate and energy in one way or another. And our senior climate reporter Casey Crownhart noticed a few trends that might provide some hints about the future. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/09/12/1103908/climate-innovators-2024/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><strong>This year&#8217;s list is available exclusively to MIT Technology Review subscribers. If you’re not a subscriber already, you </strong><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>sign up here</strong></a><strong> with a 25% discount on the usual price.</strong></p>



<p><strong>This story is from The Spark, our weekly climate and energy newsletter. </strong><a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/climate-energy-the-spark/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*"><strong>Sign up</strong></a><strong> to receive it in your inbox every Wednesday.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The must-reads</strong></p>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 The first commercial spacewalk by private citizens is underway</strong><br>And, thus far, it’s been a success. (<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/science/live-news/spacex-polaris-dawn-spacewalk-09-12-24/index.html">CNN</a>)<br>+ <em>Take a look at the long and illustrious history of spacewalks. </em>(<a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20240906-from-space-selfies-to-nearly-drowning-the-11-spacewalks-that-made-history">BBC</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 Silicon Valley is divided over California’s AI safety bill</strong><br>Big Tech is waiting anxiously for the state’s governor to make a decision. (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c5e7bf0b-cadc-4673-b2d8-daa9d89f2230">FT</a> $)<br>+ <em>What’s next for AI regulation? </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/01/05/1086203/whats-next-ai-regulation-2024/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>3 Wildfires are raging across southern California</strong><br>The state has weathered nearly three times as much acreage burn this year so far compared to the whole of 2023. (<a href="https://theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/11/injuries-california-wildfires">The Guardian</a>)<br>+ <em>Canada’s 2023 wildfires produced more emissions than fossil fuels in most countries. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/28/1103186/canada-wildfire-emissions/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>4 Broken wind turbines have major repercussions</strong><br>Multiple offshore wind projects have run into serious trouble. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/business/energy-environment/offshore-wind-blade-vineyard-wind.html">NYT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>5 The percentage of women in tech has hardly changed in 20 year</strong><br>Women and people of color face an uphill battle to get hired. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/11/big-tech-women-minorities-jobs-dei-eeoc/">WP</a> $)<br>+ <em>Why can’t tech fix its gender problem? </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/08/11/1056917/tech-fix-gender-problem/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>6 Google’s new app can turn your research into an AI podcast<br></strong>Please don’t do this, though. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/11/24242138/google-notebook-llm-ai-fake-podcasts-research">The Verge</a>)</p>



<p><strong>7 Human drivers keep crashing into Waymo robotaxis<br></strong>The company has launched a new website to put the incidents into perspective.(<a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/09/human-drivers-are-to-blame-for-most-serious-waymo-collisions/">Ars Technica</a>)<br>+ <em>What’s next for robotaxis in 2024. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/01/23/1086936/whats-next-for-robotaxis-2024/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MIT Technology Review</a>)</p>



<p><strong>8 This tiny SpaceX rival is poised to launch its first satellites<br></strong>AST SpaceMobile’s star appears to be on the rise—but for how long?(<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-11/spacex-s-tiny-rival-soars-1-300-now-comes-the-satellite-launch?srnd=phx-technology&amp;sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>9 You’ve got a fax <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f4e0.png" alt="📠" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><br>Pagers, fax machines and dumbphones are all the rage these days. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/lifestyle/careers/low-tech-executives-security-focus-a495f9e7?mod=wknd_pos1">WSJ</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>10 Have we reached peak emoji? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f632.png" alt="😲" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br></strong>The little pictograms are an illustrative language, not an ideographic one. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/09/emoji-language/679776/">The Atlantic</a> $)</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Quote of the day</strong></p>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>“A beautiful world.”</strong></p>



<p>—Billionaire businessman Jared Isaacman’s reaction as he saw Earth from space during the first privately funded spacewalk today, the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/crkmgvzl70yt#player">BBC</a> reports.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The big story</strong></p>



<p><strong>What does GPT-3 “know” about me?</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/text-bomb-fuse2c.png?fit=808,454" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong>August 2022<br><br></strong>One of the biggest stories in tech is the rise of large language models that produce text that reads like a human might have written it.<br><br>These models’ power comes from being trained on troves of publicly available human-created text hoovered up from the internet. If you’ve posted anything even remotely personal in English on the internet, chances are your data might be part of some of the world’s most popular LLMs.<br><br>Melissa Heikkilä, MIT Technology Review’s senior AI reporter, wondered what data these models might have on her—and how it could be misused. So she put OpenAI’s GPT-3 to the test. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/08/31/1058800/what-does-gpt-3-know-about-me/?utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read about what she found</a>.</p>



<p><strong>In this section yesterday we stated that Amazon had acquired iRobot. This was incorrect—the acquisition never completed. We apologize for the error.</strong></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></p>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction to brighten up your day. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/yannon_"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em></p>



<p>+ These photos of London taken on a <a href="https://www.urban75.org/watchcam/index.html">Casio camera watch</a> are a snapshot of bygone times.<br>+ If you’ve noticed elaborate painted <a href="https://www.eater.com/24230910/nail-art-cookbooks-trend-big-dip-energy-dac-biet">nails</a> making their way into your cookbooks, it’s part of a wider trend. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f485.png" alt="💅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br>+ Painting <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-vNThJpRcd/?igsh=NTFzcmNmdnBhMzdp">Paint</a>, now that’s meta.<br>+ Wow, enthusiastic <a href="https://x.com/ChrisETeigen/status/1833630587627966936">skeletons</a> are already limbering up for next month!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103921</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

